<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/android.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 13:38:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ohio Goes Google conference notes #ohiogoesgoogle</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/05/15/ohio-goes-google-conference-notes-ohiogoesgoogle/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I had the pleasure of attending my first &lt;a href="http://www.itipohio.org/OhioGoogleAppsConference.aspx"&gt;Ohio Goes Google Conference&lt;/a&gt; presented by &lt;a href="http://www.itipohio.org/"&gt;ITIP Ohio&lt;/a&gt;. The sessions I attended were very informative, I picked up quite a few different tips and ideas. (&lt;strong&gt;I'll emphasize my thoughts like this.&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Keynote speaker - Jennie Magiera @msmagiera&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google Moderator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Google Tool that nobody uses was big. Jennie Magiera talked it up, and then Sean Beavers led a session at lunch on it. Google Moderator allows for classroom participation in which the participants can post ideas and vote on these ideas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thomas Edison, Elton John, Peter Jennings all dropped out of HS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitively College Ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 out of 8, 72 out of 100 universities have gone Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docs story builder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Forms now has images, dates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;youtube.com/mathademics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blog.mrmeyer.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Top five skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critical Thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex Problem Solving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judgment and Decision Making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active Listening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers and electronics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;http://www.google.com/moderator/#15/e=209e48&amp;amp;t=209e48.40&amp;amp;f=209e48.6adb7c&amp;amp;o=30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Jennie: "Here is a copy of my keynote: (PDF) https://sites.google.com/site/­magierapresentations/ohio-goog­le-keynote And more info at my Twitter profile: https://twitter.com/msmagiera"­&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jennie was a very engaging keynote speaker!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Becoming a GMail Ninja - John Sowash&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bit.ly/sowash-PD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GTD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Priority Inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canned responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To do lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/a/sowashventures.com/gmail-ninja/home"&gt;Gmail Ninja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rapportive.com/"&gt;Rapportive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Google Apps in the Office and Beyond -  Wes Weaver - principal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's about teaching and learning&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staff meeting accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Sheets to keep track of office tasks&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;budgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guidance Dept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Google Form for student sign off of forms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track major initiatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E-mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forms&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't you feel like you're on a device all the time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your secretary available?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wes had several examples of where his secretary took the initiative and created Google Sheets documents to make her job easier. Pretty impressive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1qjiC9mBI81QofragOOJ20mzb7Jw27NRu8z7eNldL8Ss/mobilepresent?pli=1#slide=id.p"&gt;GAFE Conference Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Lunch&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speaker from Google&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I missed his name. :-(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we prepare students for a future we can't see?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web is changing how we learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sean Beavers - Google Moderator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/a/soita.org/ohio-apps-summit/home"&gt;Ohio Apps Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embed moderator with the iframe gadget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sean gave real world examples on how he had used Google Moderator in his classroom, along with a picture of him in shorts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Using Google Scripts to Automate Your Life - Jennifer Magiera&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doctopus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goobric (Doctopus extension)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FormMule (Calendar merge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had not used FormMule before, looks like it could be very handy. Especially for dealing with input into Google Forms.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lazarus-form-recovery/loljledaigphbcpfhfmgopdkppkifgno?hl=en-US&amp;amp;utm_source=chrome-ntp-launcher"&gt;Chrome Web Store - Lazarus: Form Recovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A must have Google Chrome Extension!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changing Google from Bland to Beautiful -  Eric Griffith&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Google Drawings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object based, objects can be linkable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the built in Web Clipboard to copy/paste multiple shapes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;openclipart.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;softicons.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag and drop between tabs in Chrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation will be available on YouTube through the  Ohio Goes Google web page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This was a very cool session. A lot of complaints I hear about Google Docs is that fact that it's hard to lay things out in the document. By use Google Drawing objects, you can add pizzazz to those boring Google Docs documents.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 13:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-05-15:2013/05/15/ohio-goes-google-conference-notes-ohiogoesgoogle/</guid><category>google</category><category>chrome</category><category>android</category></item><item><title>Impressions of the Nexus 7 Tablet</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2012/07/23/impressions-of-the-nexus-7-tablet/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For those that know me, ordering a Google Nexus 7 Tablet when it was
released isn't much of a surprise. I did wait a day though. :-) The
Nexus 7 Tablet joins the stable of portable devices at home, which
include a couple of iPad 1s, and iPad 3, a couple of cheap Android
tablets imported from China, an iPhone, and an HP Tablet running both
WebOS and Android Ice Cream Sandwich. My first impressions will be
mainly what I see are the pros and cons of the Nexus 7. I'm not much of
a reviewer, you can find tons of other reviews around the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardware itself is very nice, although it doesn't have the wide
viewing angles of the iPad, it's not bad. My test for viewing angles is
to lay the device flat on a table and see how well I can see the screen.
On the iPad I can use it laying flat, the Nexus 7 is also usable, just
dim enough to make me want to pick it up. Text is very nice looking,
better than the iPad 1 or Touchpad. The high resolution screen in a 7
inch size isn't "retina" ready, but it doesn't need to be. The device
fits in the front pockets of my cargo shorts, although it is too tall to
button the top flap of the cargo pockets. It's summer, so I don't know
how it will fit in dress pants, I'll find that out at the end of August.
On one side of the device there are four gold pegs that are flush with
the edge. I'm assuming this means that a dock will be available to use
the tablet in landscape mode. Over bluetooth I was able to pair a
keyboard and mouse, which makes it quite nice to use on a desk or table.
This review is being typed in Evernote using the Logitech Ultrathin
Keyboard case from my iPad 3. It's pretty neat that the home key on the
keyboard still works. In fact, most of the keys work with it (volume,
lock, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First negative to the tablet is the wide screen aspect ratio. I've read
review bashing the iPad for it's 4:3 aspect ratio, but after using the
Nexus 7 it feels like this is a good design choice with tablets. The
16:9 ratio means that the screen isn't quite wide enough when in
portrait mode, but it's not tall enough to be used in landscape mode.
When using the Nexus 7 in landscape it feels like I'm back on my
original &lt;a href="http://www.atarimuseum.com/videogames/consoles/lynx/lynx.html" title="Atari Lynx"&gt;Atari Lynx&lt;/a&gt;. Or holding on to a 2x4 by the ends. Other than
that, there aren't any real negatives about the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is another story. While Android has progressively gotten
better, it's still not up to the polished feel of iOS. There are little
things that bother me. For example, when I'm looking at my list of apps
in Google Play, I can tap on an app to get more info or to install the
app. But, when I hit the back key, I am placed back at the top of the
list, not where I was. Annoying. Also, I had to install a different
launcher since the default launcher (think home screen) doesn't work in
landscape mode. Android still doesn't have the quality of apps that iOS
does, such as TweetBot, Paper by Fifty Three, Garageband, and iMovie. I
do need to investigate multimedia creation apps. It does have a Google
Drive app that is very nice and supports editing of word processing
documents. And the Share icon available in most apps is very nice and a
lot more usable than it is in iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onscreen keyboard still needs work. I've replaced it with SwiftKey,
which is a lot better than the default keyboard, but it's still not as
fast as typing on my iPhone or iPad. Selecting text is servicable,
although not enjoyable. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you buy it? Is this a device for schools? As of right now, I'm in
a wait and see mode. I know in the past I've said to base decisions on
what is available now, not what may be available, but with the rumor
that an 8" iPad may be announced in October, I feel patience is best.
All of the software negatives I've mentioned above can be rectified with
updates, but can they be by October? If you are a school district that
is not looking at iOS devices, the Nexus 7 tablet is a worthy contender,
especially if you are a Google Apps for Education school. This could be
the start of an one to one program that is sustainable in a lot of
districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I forgot to mention two items, battery life and charging issues. First
off, battery life. It's ok, but it's no iPad. I've found that the Nexus
7 can barely make it through a day without needing charged. The reports
of 7 hour of battery life doesn't seem quite right. Using it for web,
email, IM, and a few other things (no media playback or games) has it
last maybe 6 hours. And that goes into my next rant about charging it.
This isn't a bullet point but a RANT! The Nexus 7 will only charge with
its USB cord and its charger. I've tried different chargers, including
an iPad charger, and it won't charge. It seems to show a charge when
plugged into my MacBook Air, but it doesn't charge. What is the point of
using a mini USB for the connector if I can't charge it?!?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 12:47:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2012-07-23:2012/07/23/impressions-of-the-nexus-7-tablet/</guid><category>android</category><category>nexus7</category></item><item><title>Checking out Android</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2011/01/19/checking-out-android/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As I prepare for my eTech 2011 presentation, &lt;a href="http://communities.etech.ohio.gov/planner/an-ipad-kindle-and-ipod-touch-walked-into-a-classroom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;An iPad, Kindle, and iPod
Touch walked into a classroom...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I decided that it would be
beneficial to plan on questions about Android, Android Tablets, and how
they may work in schools. The Consumer Electronics Show was held this
past week, and during it a bevy of manufacturers announced tablets, with
almost all of them running Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android is an open source operating system created at Google based on
Linux. Google allows distributes this OS free of charge to be used by
manufacturers and cellular providers on mobile devices. It competes
against other mobile operating systems such as Apple's iOS (used on the
iPhone, iPad, and iPod Touch), Microsoft Windows Phone 7, RIM Blackberry
OS, and HP's WebOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased a Motorola Droid off of eBay and received it this past week.
I've been playing around with it for the last couple of days, so this
isn't so much as a review as it is my first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;My smartphone history&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little history about my past and smartphones. I bought my first
smartphone, a Motorola Q around 2007 (I think. :-)). While it was my
first taste of online connectivity whereever I was, it was also my first
taste of, as the French would say, le pew. It was slow, ate batteries
like it was going out of style, ugly, and would just restart for now
reason. I moved on to a Samsung Omnia, then an HTC Ozone. The Ozone, at
the time (mid 2009) was Verizon's most unlocked phone. It had wifi and
the GPS was useable. All in all, not a bad phone, but still running
Windows Mobile. In August I purchased a Palm Pre Plus, which was heaven
compared to the Ozone. What holds it back is not the OS (which feels
like it could be an Apple product) but the hardware and lack of apps. As
an aside, AT&amp;amp;T does not offer service in my area, so I've gotten by with
an iPod Touch (first gen represent!) I bought in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This "First Look" will try to focus on the software itself, since in the
Android universe the quality and quantity of devices would overshadow
any comments about the hardware of the Motorola Droid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Rundown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I like:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The back button: Until I used WebOS I hadn't really thought about
    how useful a back gesture (or button) could be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Widgets: It's nice to be able to put my calendar on a screen, or a
    battery life indicator with other information about the hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of applications: So far I've been able to find an
    application for everything I need. In the market place there are
    also tons of clones of iOS games, but for the most part these are
    inferior to their iOS counterpart. Rope Cut is not Cut the Rope for
    iOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I don't like:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifcation bar: To open notifications you have to click and hold on
    the top bar and then drag down. Why I can't just click on the top
    bar for notifications I don't know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application switching: Unless I'm missing something, the only way to
    switch apps is to either exit back to home and click on the item or
    hold down the home key until the recently used applications show up.
    And heaven forbid you want to return to an open browser window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigation in applications: This is not consistant. Some apps, like
    imo.im (the instant messaging app I use) gives me a different menu
    depending on what screen I'm on, and to navigate to a certain screen
    may require several key presses and swipes through several other
    screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Uses in Education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until models are released that don't require a cellular plan,
educational uses of Android are going to be limited. This year is going
to be interesting, but if you are currently researching which OS to use
in your classroom it would be hard to recommend Android until other
models are released. Android will have two big advantages over iOS
(which is going to be its biggest competitor in the upcoming year):
price and openness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools rarely look at the total operating costs of equipment and
instead focus on purchase price. The Android tablets and handhelds will
be cheaper than their iOS cousins, and in some form factors will not
have competition (the 7 inch form factor such as the Nook).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Openness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Android is Open Source, companies can release software to
automatically manage a fleet of devices. If you've been involved with
iOS app purchases, it requires several hoops to jump through, and then
it can't even automatically install the apps. This can change with
Android. Unfortunately, this will probably mean that any price savings
you received on the purchase of the devices will be eaten in the
management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Is it a contender?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Android is a contender in the mobile space. I believe that it is a
credible threat to the iPad/iPod Touch dominance we see in schools
today. Should you wait? No. If you are looking at implementing a mobile
device initiative then don't wait for Android devices. From an
educational point of view there isn't anything that can be done on one
that can't be done on the other. The Android app store seems to be
thriving, and as more devices are sold it will only entice more
developers. Mobile devices are set to overtake personal computers &lt;a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2010/08/11/the-great-game-mobile-devices-overtaking-pcs/"&gt;any
day now&lt;/a&gt; :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What device do you use a majority of the time?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-01-19:2011/01/19/checking-out-android/</guid><category>android</category><category>cellphones</category><category>ios</category><category>mobile</category></item></channel></rss>