<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - antique</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/antique.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-27T19:38:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>The Internet Archive has added the Historical Software Archive</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/10/27/the-internet-archive-has-added-the-historical-software-archive/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-27T19:38:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-27T19:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-27:/2013/10/27/the-internet-archive-has-added-the-historical-software-archive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/historicalsoftware"&gt;Historical Software Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection contains selected historically important software packages from the Internet Archive's software archives. Through the use of in-browser emulators, it is possible to try out these items and experiment with using them, without the additional burdens of installing emulator software or tracking down the programs. Many …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/historicalsoftware"&gt;Historical Software Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection contains selected historically important software packages from the Internet Archive's software archives. Through the use of in-browser emulators, it is possible to try out these items and experiment with using them, without the additional burdens of installing emulator software or tracking down the programs. Many of these software products were the first of their kind, or utilized features and approaches that have been copied or recreated on many programs since. (historic software, vintage software, antique software)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty awesome, I spent an hour reliving Lemonade Stand. There are IBM DOS apps (such as Wordstar), Atari 8-bit (Elite), and several versions of Pac-Man.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="software"></category><category term="antique"></category></entry></feed>