<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/apple.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 21:01:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cool Mac laptop stickers</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/12/10/cool-mac-laptop-stickers/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lifehack.org/articles/lifestyle/61-original-macbook-stickers-that-make-your-laptop-even-more-awesome.html"&gt;61 Original Macbook Stickers That Make Your Laptop Even More Awesome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had the creativity to come up with some of these!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 21:01:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-12-10:2013/12/10/cool-mac-laptop-stickers/</guid><category>macintosh</category><category>apple</category><category>stickers</category></item><item><title>Apple just killed the hackintosh</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/23/apple-just-killed-the-hackintosh/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple announced yesterday at their event that the newest version of OS X, version 10.9 (Mavericks), will be free to all Macintosh computers that can run it. This is pretty amazing, we can finally keep all of our Macs on the same OS instead of us currently supporting three different versions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for hackintosh users, it means that there is no longer a way to purchase a legal copy of OS X. A hackintosh is a computer that is assembled out of parts that can be made to run OS X. It's a way to get a Mac without paying for a Mac. A lot of users of hackintosh like the challenge, like OS X, but for the most part Apple doesn't offer a hardware configuration for them. That ends now for those that try to stay as legal as possible, although a hackintosh was never quite legal. The OS X terms of service require OS X to be used on Apple labeled computers, which means even if you buy a copy it's still not quite legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this is probably not what Apple had in mind, it is the end of an era.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 10:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-23:2013/10/23/apple-just-killed-the-hackintosh/</guid><category>osx</category><category>apple</category><category>hackintosh</category></item><item><title>Follow and backchannel the Apple event today</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/22/follow-and-backchannel-the-apple-event-today/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've set up an IRC bot to feed MacRumorsLive Twitter account into the &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23eduk8me&amp;amp;uio=d4"&gt;#eduk8me IRC channel on Freenode&lt;/a&gt;. You can use the &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23eduk8me&amp;amp;uio=d4"&gt;web client&lt;/a&gt; or any IRC client to connect to the #eduk8me channel on Freenode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I'm at the Ohio ITSCO Leadership Symposium, so I don't know how much time I'll have to join. :-( )&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 10:26:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-22:2013/10/22/follow-and-backchannel-the-apple-event-today/</guid><category>apple</category><category>ipad</category><category>iphone</category></item><item><title>Post Apple event 9-10-2013 notes</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/11/post-apple-event-9-10-2013-notes/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So the latest Apple event happened. I'm always a little disappointed in them. Maybe I put my expectations too high? Anyway, for schools, the big news is the inclusion of the iWork apps (Pages, Keynote, and Numbers) and two iLife apps (iMovie and iPhoto) now available for free with new purchases. Too bad they didn't include Garageband, but for schools looking at one to one programs with iPads this is an amazing deal. Right the start the students will have some powerful creation tools that have no equal on any other handheld or tablet device. The iPhone 5C and 5S sound pretty cool, but nothing in the "gotta have it" department. Not enough for me to update my iPhone 4 yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing else in my predictions were announced, although the iPhone 4S lives on. I'm hoping for new iPads in October, just in time for the holiday season. They'll probably be released, but will they be a good enough value against the Android tablets? I mean, the Android tablets have Minecraft too. I'm so tempted by the &lt;a href="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/p/nook-hd-plus-barnes-noble/1110060512"&gt;Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Nook HD+ Tablet&lt;/a&gt;. The screen is an amazing 1920x1280 resolution and at $149 it's half the price of an iPad mini. But then I would lose TweetBot, &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/08/07/pythonista-programming-on-your-iphone-and-ipad/"&gt;Pythonista&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/08/01/drafts-for-iphone-and-ipad-is-the-app-you-never-knew-you-needed/"&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one interesting piece in the event is the inclusion of a 64-bit processor in the iPhone 5S. There have been rumors circulating about Apple testing Macbooks Airs with ARM processors like those in the iPhones. Could the iPhone 5S be a stepping stone to these new laptops? A $499 Macbook Air with 24 hour battery life sounds pretty sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 09:46:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-11:2013/09/11/post-apple-event-9-10-2013-notes/</guid><category>ios</category><category>ipad</category><category>iphone</category><category>apple</category></item><item><title>Thirty years of tech, where are we now?</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/01/29/thirty-years-of-tech-where-are-we-now/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/Apple_Lisa.jpg" /&gt;This January marks the 30 year anniversary of the Apple //e and the
Apple Lisa. While the Apple //e had profound effects on the computer
world throughout the 80s, I am in awe of how much the Apple Lisa
foretold of the computing world. No matter what your thoughts are of
Steve Jobs, the man had a knack for going "&lt;a href="http://www.complex.com/tech/2012/10/steve-jobs-quotes/move-toward-the-goal"&gt;where the puck is going to
be, not where it has been&lt;/a&gt;". Reading through &lt;a href="http://dl.ryancollins.org/BYTE%20Lisa%20Review%20-%20Feb%201983.pdf"&gt;BYTE magazine review of
the Apple Lisa&lt;/a&gt; shows what Steve was envisioning. It seems so quaint
how the writer had to describe using the "mouse", what the "desktop"
was, and how to double-click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Lisa was a failure in the marketplace and its document
centric model being bypassed by an app centric model, it did set the
stage for the direction of computers over the next 30 years. BYTE
magazine, the world's second personal computer magazine, started
publication in 1975 as a platform agnostic magazine. The Lisa was so
different that the reviewer didn't quite know how to review the
computer, and, in fact, foresaw the end of the megahertz race and the
death of computer specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting on the technical specifications of a computer toward the end
of an article is unusual for BYTE, but it emphasizes tha the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of
Lisa is more important than the what. For part of the market, at
least, the Lisa computer will change the emphasis of microcomputer
from "How much RAM does it have?" to "What can it do for me?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lisa also had a sleep feature, much like hibernate under Windows and
how iOS on the iPhone and iPad react to sleeping and waking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... thing happens when you turn the Lisa "off" (actually, it's never
completely off; it just goes into a low-power mode). In any case, when
you hit the Off button, system software automatically closes all open
files, thus transferring the information in them to their respective
floppy disks, and releses the disks from the Lisa disk drives. In
addition, the software records the status of the "desktop" so that,
when the computer is reactivated, Lisa automatically returns it to the
appearance and state it was in when the Lisa was turned "off".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that when people try to predict the future there are only two
different scenerios. The more likely gradual changes, and the so far out
there changes that the chance of them being right is slim and
unbelievable. The Lisa shows that Apple was the latter, and it amazes me
what they were thinking up in the years leading up to its release. Apple
did get inspiration on the GUI from Xerox Parc, but their additions,
such as pull-down menus, overlapping windows, are the excence of Apple,
refinement of an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xerox PARC’s innovation had been to replace the traditional computer
command line with onscreen icons. But when you clicked on an icon you
got a pop-up menu: this was the intermediary between the user’s
intention and the computer’s response. Jobs’s software team took the
graphical interface a giant step further. It emphasized “direct
manipulation.” If you wanted to make a window bigger, you just pulled
on its corner and made it bigger; if you wanted to move a window
across the screen, you just grabbed it and moved it. The Apple
designers also invented the menu bar, the pull-down menu, and the
trash can—all features that radically simplified the original Xerox
parc idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between direct and indirect manipulation—between three
buttons and one button, three hundred dollars and fifteen dollars, and
a roller ball supported by ball bearings and a free-rolling ball—is
not trivial. It is the difference between something intended for
experts, which is what Xerox PARC had in mind, and something that’s
appropriate for a mass audience, which is what Apple had in mind. PARC
was building a personal computer. Apple wanted to build a popular
computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2011/05/16/110516fa_fact_gladwell?currentPage=all"&gt;Read more:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here we are, 30 years later. A half billion iOS devices have been
sold, and more people than ever have more computing power in their
pocket then what was used to put a man on the moon. Apple now generates
almost as much revenue in a quarter than Microsoft does in a year. With
$137 billion in the bank, what do they have planned for the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your students, &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Powerful technology is available for $25
dollars&lt;/a&gt;, what are they going to create over the next 30 years?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-01-29:2013/01/29/thirty-years-of-tech-where-are-we-now/</guid><category>apple</category><category>lisa</category></item><item><title>Has Apple lost it?</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2012/09/12/has-apple-lost-it/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the iPhone 5 today and updates to the iPod line. Most of
the announcements were lackluster at best, but the event laid the
groundwork for the rumored iPad mini event in October, which could be
even more disastrous than the iPhone 5 event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 5 is a nice upgrade, thinner and lighter, but at the same
time, it doesn’t have any feature that makes it a must upgrade for me
and my iPhone 4. This is probably more of a testimonial on how good a
phone the 4 is than what the 5 brings to the table. There are features
in the next version of iOS that I won’t be able to use, such as
turn-by-turn navigation, and, I’m assuming, Facetime over cellular, but
since there are apps I can use to replace these missing features I’m not
that worried about upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more disturbing about todays event was the iPod line refresh.
Apple now sells the iPod shuffle, iPod nano, and iPod touch (the Classic
is still available, but it hasn’t seen an update in 3 years). The iPod
shuffle makes sense as an entry level music player, and at \$49, makes
it pretty affordable. After the shuffle comes the nano, which doesn’t
make sense at all. At least the 6th generation nano had a cool look and
could be used as a watch, this 7th generation looks like an iPod touch,
works like an iPod touch, but isn’t an iPod touch. Why would Apple waste
engineering sources on the nano? They priced it at \$149, only \$50 less
than the entry level iPod touch that includes the same amount of
storage. I just can’t think of a use case where the nano makes a better
purchase than the iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the iPod touch. At the \$199 price point, they’re now
selling the 4th generation iPod touch with 16Gb instead of just 8GB. No
other changes in the now two year old device. If you want the new iPod
touch which has several of the goodies of the iPhone 5, be prepared to
shell out \$299. You do get 32Gb at this price but is it worth a third
more than the iPod touch 4th generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the pricing of the iPod touch which is the most worrisome. Making a
guess about the iPad mini launch next month, I bet that Apple will drop
the iPad 2 and put the iPad mini in at the \$399 price. This would hand
the Christmas shopping season to Amazon, Google, and possibly Barnes and
Noble. The software for iOS is heads and shoulders above what is
available for Android, but when a parent can pick up two Kindle Fire HDs
for the price of one iPad mini, what choice do you think they’re going
to make? I really doubt they’d price the iPad mini at the same price as
the new iPod touch, but let’s say they do. It would still be a third
higher than the Kindle Fire HD, although closer in price to the Nexus 7
32GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has solid devices, well built, but their pricing expectations are
all over the place. To me, it makes sense to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep the shuffle at \$49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;place the old nano form factor (but with bluetooth) with 8GB at \$99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 4th gen (8GB) (add bluetooth 4.0 and IPS screen) at \$149&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 5th gen (16GB) at \$199&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad mini (16GB) at \$299&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 2 (16GB) at \$399&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 3 (16GB) at \$499&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see more and more kids getting Kindle Fires, which is now at \$159.
Apple has dominated the tablet space (and the mobile phone space in
profits), but if they don’t price their products more aggressively, they
will lose that dominance. Right now, a \$299 iPad mini would be a tough
sell in my school district when I get get a Nexus 7 (which has better
integration with Google Drive) for \$199. Forget about a \$399 iPad
mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. Signs that Steve Jobs is gone: he would never have added that hand
strap to the iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 18:38:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2012-09-12:2012/09/12/has-apple-lost-it/</guid><category>apple</category><category>iPad</category><category>iPhone</category><category>ipodtouch</category></item><item><title>FIrst impressions of the MacBook Air 11"</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2010/10/27/first-impressions-of-the-macbook-air-11/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since Steve Jobs blessed my MacBook Air and I received it two day early,
I've had almost a week to investigate the 11" MacBook Air. I opted to
max it out, so it has 4GB of RAM, 128GB Solid State Drive (SSD) and the
1.6GHz Intel Core 2 Duo CPU. The educational price was \$1,329, which
was almost more than I was willing to spend, but so far, it's been worth
it. The MBA is replacing an original 1.83GHz Intel Core Duo MacBook,
which had been upgraded to 2GB of RAM and a 7,200 RPM 200GB hard drive.
Before I ordered the MBA I did some quick calculations, and CPU wise,
the MBA should be as fast as my old MacBook (the Intel Core 2 Duo is
10-15% faster than the Intel Core Duo, and the MBA has a front bus of
800MHz compared to my MacBook's 667MHz). Adding more memory and the
faster drive, it is faster than the MacBook that replaced it.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: large;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the 11"?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the 11" over the 13" Air models was an easy decision. My goal
was portability. Screen size doesn't really play into it, since at work
I have a 24" LCD and at home I have a 23" LCD. I was never very
impressed with the older 13" Air model. It was still the same size as my
MacBook, only thinner. If screen size does matter to you, I would think
long and hard before I would buy the 13" Air over a MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: large;"&gt;Quick!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the machine, the quickness is very surprising. Of course, the SSD
gets most of the credit. When discussing the speed of the machine versus
other Macintosh models, a good analogy is in cars, electric cars versus
gas. Car motor power is measured by two different factors, horsepower
and torque. Horsepower is where you get your speed, and torque is how
fast you can get to your horsepower. Now an interesting thing happens
with electric cars versus gas. In a drag race, the electric car has the
advantage at the start since an electric motor has 100% of its torque
available at 0 RPMs, whereas a gasoline engine requires the motor to hit
a certain number of RPMs before torque is available. Depending on the
length of the race, an electric car can win every time against a more
powerful gasoline powered car. This is the same feeling with the MacBook
Air. With the SSD, the computer is faster than more powerful computers
for a wide range of tasks a user may do during the day. While a core i7
MacBook Pro is going to beat the MacBook Air at rendering video, if the
race is shorter, say launching Safari and browsing the web, the MacBook
Air is going to win. Can this machine be my main machine? It already is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: large;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Size wise, it is about as thick as my iPad (in the Apple Case) is, and
weight wise it's pretty much a tie with the iPad. In fact, I handed my
MBA and iPad to my sister-in-law and asked her which was heavier, and
she said the iPad! Although the MBA has about the same depth and
thickness as the iPad, it is around 1.5" longer. Not as portable as the
iPad, but pretty close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen size at first took a little getting used to. I wasn't too
worried about the smaller screen, but the first couple of days of using
it I kept wanting to bump up the font sizes when browsing. This need
went away, and I've now gotten used to the size of the fonts on the
screen. (By the way, when is a browser going to give me the ability to
double-click on an article and have it zoom into that text, like my iPad
and iPod Touch does?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: large;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Odds and ends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build quality is excellent, the full size keyboard is great, and the
touchpad is amazing. My extra MacBook charger works with it too! I
ordered mini-display port adapters for \$30 from &lt;a href="http://www.monoprice.com/"&gt;monoprice.com&lt;/a&gt; for
VGA, DVI, and HDMI. Compare that to the \$29 Apple wants for just the
VGA adapter! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: large;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ugly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually don't really have any cons against the MacBook Air 11". Twice
I've woken it up and the backlight didn't come on, but it hasn't
happened enough for me to worry about it yet (and I've got 11 more
months to decide whether to buy AppleCare for it :-). It's almost a
perfect travel companion, and if Apple could shave another inch or so
from the width it would be perfect!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have the MacBook Airs gotten you interested in a Mac? Would you buy an
Air and run Windows 7 or Linux on it?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 11:23:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-10-27:2010/10/27/first-impressions-of-the-macbook-air-11/</guid><category>apple</category><category>macbookair</category><category>mba</category></item><item><title>My Apple Event predictions</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2010/10/19/my-apple-event-predictions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow Apple is holding an event to announce new products for the Mac.
What will be announced is anyone's guess, but here's what my intuition
is telling me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new MacBook Air is pretty much a given. The rumors are pretty
    strong that there will be an 11.6" and 13.3" Macbook Air, and that
    they'll be more affordable than the current Air. I'm hoping there is
    an 11.6" because I'm ready to upgrade my original MacBook! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New MacBook Pros. This is something I haven't read anywhere, but I'm
    pretty sure it's going to happen. Why? I ordered two for the school
     district on October 8th with a shipping time of 3-5 days. A week
    later I received a notification that they would ship between Oct.
    21-26. Notice the first day is the day after the Apple Event. And
    now today I received notification that they will not ship until Dec.&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple must have something planned for the MacBook Pros, and
originally thought they would be able to ship them on the 21st, but
something happened and they're planning on shipping them 6 weeks
later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS X 10.7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iLife '11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac App Store - Apple added the ability to sign applications in OS X
    10.5 Leopard, and with the success of the iOS App Store will create
    an App store for the Mac. Unfortunately it will still go through
    iTunes, because for some reason everything has to go through iTunes
    with Apple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything I missed that you want to see Apple unveil?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 14:20:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-10-19:2010/10/19/my-apple-event-predictions/</guid><category>apple</category><category>macbook</category><category>osx</category></item><item><title>The iPad has landed</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2010/04/03/the-ipad-has-landed/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Braving almost 70? weather I arrived at the Easton Apple store at 7:40
am to pick up my reserved 32gb iPad. I'll have a longer review later,
but I'm currently typing this blog post while using the Wordpress app
and sitting in Cos?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, So cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 08:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-04-03:2010/04/03/the-ipad-has-landed/</guid><category>apple</category><category>iPad</category></item><item><title>HIW (How I Work): The Apple MacBook</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2008/12/02/hiw-how-i-work-the-apple-macbook/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/nav-c-macbook.jpg" /&gt;I am asked quite often how I can keep up with everything in regards
to educational technology, software, and hardware. After some
reflection, I realized that it would make a good series of articles, so
I'm going to write up &lt;strong&gt;How I Work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up is probably the most important component of my technology
arsenal, my &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/SP31"&gt;Apple MacBook&lt;/a&gt;. During the spring of 2006 I was
researching upgrading my &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/support/imac/g4/"&gt;17" iMac&lt;/a&gt; to a new &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/support/macbookpro/"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The plan
was to buy a beefy enough MacBook Pro that I wouldn't want to upgrade
for awhile. I specc'ed out the MacBook Pro that I wanted to be almost
\$2,500! I wasn't happy being stuck with getting such a large laptop,
but I was in luck that Apple then announced the &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/SP31"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt;. After realizing I could buy a MacBook and an iMac for the same
price as the MacBook Pro, I ordered my &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/SP31"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt;. After
using it, I realized I didn't even need a desktop at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/SP31"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion/"&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt;, I get the best
of all worlds. I run OS X 10.5 mainly, but have a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windowsxp/pro/default.mspx"&gt;Windows XP&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.ubuntu.com/"&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; virtual machines also installed on the machine. Since the
original purchase I've bumped the memory from 1GB to 2GB and the hard
drive from 80GB to 200GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, come summer 2009 when I'll be looking at upgrading I
don't know what I'll do. The new MacBook's lack of firewire is almost a
deal killer for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am at home I hook my &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/SP31"&gt;MacBook&lt;/a&gt; up to a 17" LCD
monitor and use a cheap [\$30 Micro Innovations wireless keyboard and
mouse I purchased from Wal-mart][] (mine is a dark grey, not the hideous
color from the picture). The combo works pretty well, except sometimes I
have to unplug and re-plug the USB dongle that works with the set when I
wake the MacBook up from sleep. That's also where I keep an external
hard drive to maintain my laptops backups using OS X's &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/timemachine.html"&gt;Time Machine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[\$30 Micro Innovations wireless keyboard and mouse I purchased from
  Wal-mart]: http://www.walmart.com/catalog/product.do?product_id=8144837&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 12:49:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2008-12-02:2008/12/02/hiw-how-i-work-the-apple-macbook/</guid><category>apple</category><category>hiw</category><category>imac</category><category>macbook</category><category>macbook pro</category><category>vmware</category><category>walmart</category></item></channel></rss>