<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - battery</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/battery.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-11-10T15:09:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Portable USB battery options</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/11/10/portable-usb-battery-options/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-10T15:09:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-11-10T15:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-11-10:/2013/11/10/portable-usb-battery-options/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href="http://www.scottsibberson.com/2013/11/lenmar-power-pack.html"&gt;Scott's post on the Lenmar Power Pack&lt;/a&gt; and that reminded me that I had been wanting to post my portable power options. My first USB charger was a Duracell model I picked up at Meijer on the discountinued rack several years ago. It worked ok, but since them …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href="http://www.scottsibberson.com/2013/11/lenmar-power-pack.html"&gt;Scott's post on the Lenmar Power Pack&lt;/a&gt; and that reminded me that I had been wanting to post my portable power options. My first USB charger was a Duracell model I picked up at Meijer on the discountinued rack several years ago. It worked ok, but since them I've upgraded. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up is the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B006FXUS1C"&gt;Tekkeon MP1580 TEKCHARGE Mobile Power Pack and Battery Charger&lt;/a&gt;. I bought this one because it can take regular AA batteries. I also bought an 8 pack of the Sanyo Eneloop batteries. This way I can use the charger twice before I have to find an outlet. It's also pretty compact. Unfortunately, AA batteries aren't the best way to charge an iPhone, only bringing it up 30-40%. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second is a &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B0073WV1UQ"&gt;Mophie Juice Pack&lt;/a&gt; for my iPhone. This one I almost always use anytime I know I'm not going to be near an outlet for an entire day. It will bring my phone up to about 60%. It's a little nicer than the USB chargers since I don't have to mess around with cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final device I use is the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B00AANQLRI"&gt;Jackery Giant 10400mAh Premium Portable High Capacity Dual-Port External Battery Power Bank Backup Charger&lt;/a&gt;. This thing can charge my iPhone several times and I've read that it will charge my iPad 3 once (I haven't had a chance to try that out). It is heavy though, and bulkier than the above mentioned devices. I always carry it in my bag though, and if I am going out with friends I'll grab it and a couple of cables so I can charge their phones too (although I don't have an Apple device that require a Lightning cable, so I can't charge those).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. For the Great Ohio Bike Adventure back in June I bought the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B00828VFT2"&gt;AGPtek 5000mAh Solar Power Dual USB External Battery Pack and Charger&lt;/a&gt;. Although it does have two USB ports, one is for charging the battery. As a backup battery it worked fine, but the solar panel is basically on there for emergencies. After a full day of riding with it in the sun I could maybe get 5% charge onto my phone. That would be great if I was stuck somewhere and had to do a quick call or text, but I wouldn't buy it for it's solar panel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="usb"></category><category term="battery"></category></entry></feed>