<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/checklist.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 10:05:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Attending a conference? Here's my conference checklist #iPadSymposiumUA</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2014/05/02/attending-a-conference-heres-my-conference-checklist-ipadsymposiumua/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This Saturday I will be presenting at the University of Akron's iPad Symposium. As I've attended numerous conferences throughout my professional career, I've started to realize I should create a to do list so I don't forget anything before a conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Charge my devices and battery packs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My usual compliment of devices I take to a conference consists of my laptop, iPad, and iPhone. Along with charging them, I also have a battery case for my iPhone and a Jackery Giant USB battery pack that needs to be charged. Multi-day conferences are not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Set up IFTTT to capture my notes and tweets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've started to use Twitter to write my notes during a conference and  &lt;a href="http://ifttt.com"&gt;If This Then That&lt;/a&gt; to capture them. The recipe I use looks for any of my tweets with the conference hashtag, and if found, it appends that tweet to a text file in &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of the conference I'll have an entire text file with everything I want to save from the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="IFTTT Hashtag Recipe" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/Screen%20Shot%202014-05-02%20at%207.56.07%20AM.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Set up a keyboard shortcut for the conference hashtag&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hashtag for the conference Saturday is #iPadSymposiumUA. What I did on my iPhone and iPad is create a keyboard shortcut (Settings -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; Keyboard -&amp;gt; Shortcuts). The shortcut is &lt;strong&gt;iii&lt;/strong&gt; which expands to #iPadSymposiumUA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Charge my name tag&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name tag I've started to use is a 4 generation iPod Touch running Keynote. I have a lanyard that connects to the dock connector, and I created a 3 slide presentation that continually loops. Keynote keeps the display on while showing a presentation. If I shut it off during sessions, the battery lasts an entire day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Gas up the car, get some cash and Ho Hos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, how frustrating it can be to get in your car for a multi-hour trip and realize you have to stop for gas. Even though I hardly use cash anymore, it's a good idea to have a few bucks on you, just in case. The Ho Hos? They're self explanatory. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 10:05:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-05-02:2014/05/02/attending-a-conference-heres-my-conference-checklist-ipadsymposiumua/</guid><category>conference</category><category>checklist</category><category>eduk8me</category></item></channel></rss>