<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/commentary.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 17:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>The iPod Touch</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2008/03/02/the-ipod-touch/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I picked up an iPod Touch on Saturday, and am I impressed. I have been
testing out the Nokia N800, but when it comes to Internet usability, the
Touch wins hands down. Surfing is very, very usable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still getting used to the onscreen keyboard, but it is already a lot
better than the N800. The question I have remaining, "Is the touch more
useful I'm the classroom than the Asus eeePC?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2008 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2008-03-02:2008/03/02/the-ipod-touch/</guid><category>Commentary</category><category>iPod Touch</category></item><item><title>eTech Ohio Technology Conference</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2008/02/03/etech-ohio-technology-conference/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href="http://johnrappold.org/blog/?p=402"&gt;John's blog post&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, I realized that not only
haven't I posted anything, I haven't even begun to look at what sessions
I want to go to at the eTech conference. Since I present at 8:00am
Monday morning, I've been more focused on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the Online Conference Planner I've begun to setup the sessions I
want to go to, and I will be publishing my &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=rcpkdvctjc9h4biid39aja0lek%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;ctz=America/New_York"&gt;calendar through Google
Calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 09:37:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2008-02-03:2008/02/03/etech-ohio-technology-conference/</guid><category>Commentary</category></item><item><title>Can Wikipedia can be saved for our schools?</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2006/01/23/can-wikipedia-can-be-saved-for-our-schools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Andy Carvin on his blog presents a case for &lt;a href="http://www.andycarvin.com/archives/2005/07/turning_wikiped.html"&gt;Turning Wikipedia into an
Asset for Schools&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of blindly following what's in Wikipedia,
use it to present "teachers with an excellent authentic learning
activity in which students can demonstrate their skills as scholars":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...]Take a group of fifth grade students and break them into groups,
with each group picking a topic that interests them. Any topic.
Dolphins, horses, hockey, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, send the groups of kids to Wikipedia to look up the topic they
selected. [...] The horse, for example, has an extensive entry on the
website. It certainly looks accurate and informative, but is it?
Unfortunately, there are no citations for any of the facts claimed
about horses on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...]The group of students breaks down the content on the page into
manageable chunks, each with a certain amount of facts that need to be
verified. The students then spend the necessary time to fact-check the
content.&lt;br /&gt;
 Once the Wikipedia entry has been fact-checked, the teacher creates a
Wikipedia login for the class. They go to the entry's talk page and
present their findings, laying out every idea that needs to be
corrected. Then, they edit the actual entry to make the corrections,
with all sources cited. Similarly, for all the parts of the entry
they've verified as accurate, they list sources confirming it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 20:57:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2006-01-23:2006/01/23/can-wikipedia-can-be-saved-for-our-schools/</guid><category>Commentary</category><category>Headlines</category></item></channel></rss>