<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - daycare</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/daycare.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-09-14T22:39:49-04:00</updated><entry><title>Six months too young for the iPad?</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/09/14/six-months-too-young-for-the-ipad/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-14T22:39:49-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-14T22:39:49-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-14:/2013/09/14/six-months-too-young-for-the-ipad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2013/09/discovering-that-your-18-month-old-is-using-an-ipad-in-pre-school/279438/"&gt;Discovering That Your 18-Month-Old Is Using an iPad in Pre-School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recent summer day in Nashville, Kara Teising opened her Facebook page for a lunchtime scroll through her timeline when she discovered a photo posted by her son’s daycare: an image of her 18-month-old son surrounded by other …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2013/09/discovering-that-your-18-month-old-is-using-an-ipad-in-pre-school/279438/"&gt;Discovering That Your 18-Month-Old Is Using an iPad in Pre-School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recent summer day in Nashville, Kara Teising opened her Facebook page for a lunchtime scroll through her timeline when she discovered a photo posted by her son’s daycare: an image of her 18-month-old son surrounded by other toddlers, their chubby faces glued to a brightly colored, animated screen of an iPad. .... After several discussions with the school’s leadership, Teising and her husband decided to pull their son out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do parents of today hold some ideology of childhood that doesn't include electronics? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shared my theory with Kirkorian –that we parents might idealize a childhood without technology as better. “I often hear ‘grown ups’ talk about the inherent value of ‘real’ objects over technology,” she said, “but frankly I don't see a difference (and there's no research to suggest there is one) between a stick and an iPad. Of course kids should have time to explore the natural environment and interact with other people. A more realistic question is whether an hour or two of touch-screens per day is going to devastate permanently cognitive/social development. It's unlikely, but we just don't know yet, and any answer will depend heavily on program content and the characteristics of individual children.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a difference between a stick and an iPad?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ipad"></category><category term="preschool"></category><category term="daycare"></category></entry></feed>