<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/dd.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2010-06-29T08:05:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Bought my 6 year old daughter an iPhone</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2010/06/29/bought-my-6-year-old-daught-an-iphone/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-29T08:05:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-06-29:2010/06/29/bought-my-6-year-old-daught-an-iphone/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My daughter is an avid reader and writer, so as she is preparing to go
into 1st grade, I wanted to give her an outlet to publish online. What I
did was set up a Tumblr blog for her at &lt;a href="http://gracyl.ryancollins.org"&gt;gracyl.ryancollins.org&lt;/a&gt;. I
chose Tumblr because it allows her to easily post through email, so she
can post through her computer, my cellphone or her mom's cellphone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the process of setting her up, I decided I wanted a more portable way
for her to write posts. I thought about giving her my 1G iPod Touch, but
went on eBay to look at the iPhone 3G (I wonder how you are supposed to
use the plural of iPhone 3G?). They seem to be selling for right around
\$150, so I bid on a couple and finally won one at \$138. I'm not
planning on activating cell service on it and will use it &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/ht3406"&gt;just like an
iPod Touch&lt;/a&gt;. The advantage of the iPhone 3G of the iPod Touch is the
inclusion of the camera and GPS (I'm not certain the GPS works without
cell service, I guess I'll find out).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Tumblr app installed, she will be able to post to her blog
anywhere she has wifi access. I'm excited to see how well it works, and
if she'll stay away from Tap Fish long enough to find out what else the
iPhone can do!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dd"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="iPod Touch"></category></entry></feed>