<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - eduk8me</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/eduk8me.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2016-02-08T09:44:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>My conference checkist - 2016 edition</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/08/my-conference-checkist-2016-edition/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-08T09:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-08T09:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-08:/2016/02/08/my-conference-checkist-2016-edition/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I get ready for the Ohio Educational Technology Conference this week I though it would be a good idea to &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/05/02/attending-a-conference-heres-my-conference-checklist-ipadsymposiumua/"&gt;revisit my conference checklist&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Charge devices and battery packs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My devices I'm currently taking are a 2010 MacBook Pro, iPad Mini 3, and iPhone 6 Plus. I'd like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I get ready for the Ohio Educational Technology Conference this week I though it would be a good idea to &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/05/02/attending-a-conference-heres-my-conference-checklist-ipadsymposiumua/"&gt;revisit my conference checklist&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Charge devices and battery packs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My devices I'm currently taking are a 2010 MacBook Pro, iPad Mini 3, and iPhone 6 Plus. I'd like to take my Kindle and a Raspberry Pi, but I get tired of lugging a 30 lb backpack around for three days. My current USB battery pack of choice is the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0085OB0IE?psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_search_detailpage"&gt;PowerGen 12000mAh External Battery&lt;/a&gt; (unfortunately, it looks like it is now unavailable). The nice thing about this battery pack is that it supports pass through charging, which means I can power a Raspberry Pi and plug it in to charge without disrupting the Pi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the conference I'll rely on my iPad Mini or iPhone a majority of the time. Even though &lt;a href="http://eduk8.me/2016/01/running-a-mac-on-battery-youll-probably-want-to-switch-to-safari/"&gt;I now get almost 7 hours of battery life out of my MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, that's still not enough to get through three days of a conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Set up IFTTT to capture my notes and tweets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If This Then That (IFTTT) is a web service that can interact with services and do things on your behalf. To facilitate my note taking during conferences, I set up IFTTT to automatically append all of my tweets with the conference hashtag to a file. With this set up, I can share what I learn in the sessions and automatically save them to my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Set up a keyboard shortcut for the conference hashtag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, to make it easier to use the conference hashtag, I will use the iPhone keyboard shortcuts and set &lt;strong&gt;ooo&lt;/strong&gt; to be the conference hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#oetc16&lt;/strong&gt;. I'll also have &lt;strong&gt;oxx&lt;/strong&gt; set for the OETCx unconference hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#oetcx&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Add a workflow to Drafts for tweeting during the conference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drafts for iOS is my go to app for creating notes and automating tasks on my iPhone. For conferences, I'll set up a workflow that will tweet the draft with the conference hashtags. With this set up, I click Drafts, type my tweet, and then run the conference tweeting workflow which will append the conference hashtag to the Tweet and then send it. Pretty nifty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Get gas, cash, and Ho Hos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ho Hos should not need an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="conference"></category><category term="checklist"></category><category term="eduk8me"></category></entry><entry><title>My blogging at RyanCollins.org vs Eduk8.me</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/04/my-blogging-at-ryancollins-org-vs-eduk8-me/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-04T09:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-04T09:37:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-04:/2016/02/04/my-blogging-at-ryancollins-org-vs-eduk8-me/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been struggling with my online identity and what I want to share. Too often I try to spread myself too thin, but if I'm not trying to learn it all I feel like I'm missing something. If you haven't noticed, I've taken a different route with &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org"&gt;RyanCollins.org&lt;/a&gt; and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been struggling with my online identity and what I want to share. Too often I try to spread myself too thin, but if I'm not trying to learn it all I feel like I'm missing something. If you haven't noticed, I've taken a different route with &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org"&gt;RyanCollins.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://eduk8.me"&gt;Eduk8.me&lt;/a&gt;. For now I'm going to use &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org"&gt;RyanCollins.org&lt;/a&gt; for more nerdy pastimes, such as &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2016/01/27/set-your-raspberry-pi-up-for-wifi-roaming/"&gt;Raspberry Pi hacking&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2016/01/15/using-rss-like-its-1990/"&gt;command line tomfoolery&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://eduk8.me"&gt;Eduk8.me&lt;/a&gt; for more general purpose Edtech tips.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ryancollins.org"></category><category term="eduk8me"></category></entry><entry><title>Attending a conference? Here's my conference checklist #iPadSymposiumUA</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2014/05/02/attending-a-conference-heres-my-conference-checklist-ipadsymposiumua/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-05-02T10:05:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-05-02T10:05:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-05-02:/2014/05/02/attending-a-conference-heres-my-conference-checklist-ipadsymposiumua/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Saturday I will be presenting at the University of Akron's iPad Symposium. As I've attended numerous conferences throughout my professional career, I've started to realize I should create a to do list so I don't forget anything before a conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Charge my devices and battery packs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My usual …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Saturday I will be presenting at the University of Akron's iPad Symposium. As I've attended numerous conferences throughout my professional career, I've started to realize I should create a to do list so I don't forget anything before a conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1. Charge my devices and battery packs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My usual compliment of devices I take to a conference consists of my laptop, iPad, and iPhone. Along with charging them, I also have a battery case for my iPhone and a Jackery Giant USB battery pack that needs to be charged. Multi-day conferences are not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Set up IFTTT to capture my notes and tweets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've started to use Twitter to write my notes during a conference and  &lt;a href="http://ifttt.com"&gt;If This Then That&lt;/a&gt; to capture them. The recipe I use looks for any of my tweets with the conference hashtag, and if found, it appends that tweet to a text file in &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of the conference I'll have an entire text file with everything I want to save from the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="IFTTT Hashtag Recipe" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/Screen%20Shot%202014-05-02%20at%207.56.07%20AM.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Set up a keyboard shortcut for the conference hashtag&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hashtag for the conference Saturday is #iPadSymposiumUA. What I did on my iPhone and iPad is create a keyboard shortcut (Settings -&amp;gt; General -&amp;gt; Keyboard -&amp;gt; Shortcuts). The shortcut is &lt;strong&gt;iii&lt;/strong&gt; which expands to #iPadSymposiumUA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Charge my name tag&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name tag I've started to use is a 4 generation iPod Touch running Keynote. I have a lanyard that connects to the dock connector, and I created a 3 slide presentation that continually loops. Keynote keeps the display on while showing a presentation. If I shut it off during sessions, the battery lasts an entire day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Gas up the car, get some cash and Ho Hos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, how frustrating it can be to get in your car for a multi-hour trip and realize you have to stop for gas. Even though I hardly use cash anymore, it's a good idea to have a few bucks on you, just in case. The Ho Hos? They're self explanatory. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="conference"></category><category term="checklist"></category><category term="eduk8me"></category></entry></feed>