<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/howto.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-08-30T10:36:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>How to record touches and gestures for iOS screencasts</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/08/30/how-to-record-touches-and-gestures-for-ios-screencasts/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-30T10:36:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-08-30:2013/08/30/how-to-record-touches-and-gestures-for-ios-screencasts/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight I was playing around with Assistive Touch on my iPhone. In the Accessibility Settings, Assistive Touch places a "button" on the screen. This button gives the user access to certain capabilities, such as the ability to push a virtual &lt;strong&gt;home&lt;/strong&gt; button. Playing around tonight I went into the &lt;strong&gt;Favorites&lt;/strong&gt; area. This lets you record a gesture, with which you can play by pressing a button in this &lt;strong&gt;Favorites&lt;/strong&gt; area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in my playing around, I created my first gesture, which was just a tap. Once I added this saved gesture as a favorite I turned it on. Lo and behold, I had a blue circle on screen, which I could move around and when I released it showed tap. I then realized that one could turn this on when recording iPad or iPhone/iPod Touch screencasts and the taps would show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt;, tap &lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt; and on the left, select &lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Accessibility" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/AssistiveTouch2013.08.29_3-m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under &lt;strong&gt;Physical and Motor&lt;/strong&gt;, tab &lt;strong&gt;Assistive Touch&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Assistive Touch" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/AssistiveTouch2013.08.29_2-m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn on &lt;strong&gt;Assistive Touch&lt;/strong&gt; and then tab &lt;strong&gt;Create a new Gesture...&lt;/strong&gt;. To create the touch gesture, just tap. To save the gesture, tap &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt; in the upper right corner. Name it &lt;strong&gt;Touch&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Create New Gesture" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/AssistiveTouch2013.08.29_0-m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Save Gesture" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/AssistiveTouch2013.08.29_1-m.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now launch the app you want to record, tap the assistive touch button, select favorites and your newly created gesture, &lt;strong&gt;Touch&lt;/strong&gt;. A blue circle will follow your figure around the screen, showing a tap when you release your finger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, no other gestures work other than the current one selected. You also probably will want to create some sliding gestures, which would allow you to show a slide in the screencast. If you are switching gestures, you will probably want to cut out the selection of the gesture in your favorite movie editing application.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ios"></category><category term="screencast"></category><category term="howto"></category></entry></feed>