<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - inform</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/inform.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-06-28T09:13:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>My summer plans 2013</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/06/28/my-summer-plans-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-28T09:13:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-06-28T09:13:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-06-28:/2013/06/28/my-summer-plans-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to let a little thing like summer already being 3 weeks in the past to stop me from making a few goals on what I want to do this summer. :-) And since I'm more likely to accomplish things if I write them down, I decided to post …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to let a little thing like summer already being 3 weeks in the past to stop me from making a few goals on what I want to do this summer. :-) And since I'm more likely to accomplish things if I write them down, I decided to post them here for all to see and to also keep me on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read three novels: &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Catching Fire&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;To Kill a Mockingbird&lt;/em&gt;. I usually get so caught up with non-fiction (including all my RSS feeds) that I don't read as much fiction as I should. There really isn't any particular reason for reading these, except for the fact that two of them have movies in 2013.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an interactive fiction game in Inform 7. Interactive fiction may be somewhat of a dead genre but I think it's a fascinating way to create a story. I bought &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Creating-Interactive-Fiction-Inform-7/dp/1435455061"&gt;Creating Interactive Fiction with Inform 7 by Aaron Reed&lt;/a&gt; in September of 2010. I think it's about time to put it to use!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a &lt;a href="http://www.littlefreelibrary.org/"&gt;Little Free Library&lt;/a&gt;. These are the book equivalent of take a penny/leave a penny.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish my super secret web tool.... :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there anything you're doing this summer?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="if"></category><category term="inform"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="books"></category><category term="library"></category></entry></feed>