<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/integration.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 21:22:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Current level of technology integration, what is advanced?</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/30/current-level-of-technology-integration-what-is-advanced/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight on #OETchat the first question was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1: What do you believe is the current level or state of technology integration in schools &amp;amp; how effective is it? #OETchat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I answered that most were beginners, and some were intermediate. Then I said that none were advanced. Do you know of any districts or schools in Ohio that are advanced with technology integration? Responding to comments I started to try to picture what advanced means. I guess at the basic level advanced means that students are creating more than consuming. Creating in this sense means more than just using an office suite. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are other aspects of advanced? Maker spaces? Coding? Digital publishing and story telling? What else?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 21:22:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-30:2013/10/30/current-level-of-technology-integration-what-is-advanced/</guid><category>edtech</category><category>integration</category></item><item><title>Technology and Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/02/technology-and-maslows-hierarchy-of-needs/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://site.xavier.edu/crable/IT_Value_Maslow.pdf"&gt;The IT Value Hierarchy: Using Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs as a Metaphor for Gauging the Maturity Level of Information Technology Use within Competitive Organizations&lt;/a&gt;(PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although information technology products and services may be equally available, the innovative use of IT to create competitive differentiation has clearly been achieved y many organizations. What IT executives often lack is a contextual framework in which to explain the path to increasing value for their firms. The authors believe that this framework can be explained through the use of a needs hierarchy based on a comparison to the human psychological needs hierarchy described by Abraham Maslow more than sixty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parallels to technology in education is uncanny. This paper provides a nice framework for the technology planning process. Just replace &lt;strong&gt;IT executives&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;staff, administration, BOE, and community&lt;/strong&gt;. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 10:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-02:2013/10/02/technology-and-maslows-hierarchy-of-needs/</guid><category>maslow</category><category>integration</category></item><item><title>Why are you integrating technology?</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/23/why-are-you-integrating-technology/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://georgecouros.ca/blog/archives/4125"&gt;School plus&lt;/a&gt; I have a new favorite quote for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When Gutenberg invented the printing press, we didn’t have Europe plus books. Instead we had a whole new Europe."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding technology, you want a whole new school, not just school plus technology. Go over and read &lt;a href="http://georgecouros.ca/blog/archives/4125"&gt;George Coursos' full post&lt;/a&gt;, he's hit it out of the park yet again!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 10:37:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-23:2013/09/23/why-are-you-integrating-technology/</guid><category>quote</category><category>integration</category></item></channel></rss>