<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - ipad</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/ipad.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-11-22T22:26:33-05:00</updated><entry><title>One iPad per classroom</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/11/22/one-ipad-per-classroom/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-22T22:26:33-05:00</published><updated>2013-11-22T22:26:33-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-11-22:/2013/11/22/one-ipad-per-classroom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ipad4schools.org/2013/10/23/the-one-ipad-classroom/"&gt;The “One iPad” Classroom&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been allocated just one iPad for your classroom then you have very different issues to 1-to-1 classrooms as the iPad is not designed as a shared device. But don’t despair! There are apps for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via: &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/iPadWells/statuses/392877999122432001?screen_name=iPadWells"&gt;@iPadWells&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/wirededucator"&gt;@WiredEducator&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ipad4schools.org/2013/10/23/the-one-ipad-classroom/"&gt;The “One iPad” Classroom&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been allocated just one iPad for your classroom then you have very different issues to 1-to-1 classrooms as the iPad is not designed as a shared device. But don’t despair! There are apps for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via: &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/iPadWells/statuses/392877999122432001?screen_name=iPadWells"&gt;@iPadWells&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/wirededucator"&gt;@WiredEducator&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ipad"></category></entry><entry><title>Using an iPad with your reading workshop</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/11/09/using-an-ipad-with-your-reading-workshop/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-09T23:49:21-05:00</published><updated>2013-11-09T23:49:21-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-11-09:/2013/11/09/using-an-ipad-with-your-reading-workshop/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/top-teaching/2013/09/how-technology-can-support-and-enhance-your-reading-workshop"&gt;How Technology Can Support and Enhance Your Reading Workshop&lt;/a&gt; writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with most of my planning, I started with the end in mind. I thought to myself, "What if students could jot their thinking down, in real time, and receive feedback without interrupting the workshop?" Even if they didn't receive …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/top-teaching/2013/09/how-technology-can-support-and-enhance-your-reading-workshop"&gt;How Technology Can Support and Enhance Your Reading Workshop&lt;/a&gt; writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with most of my planning, I started with the end in mind. I thought to myself, "What if students could jot their thinking down, in real time, and receive feedback without interrupting the workshop?" Even if they didn't receive feedback in the moment, could they at least jot their notes down to share at a more appropriate time? This is when I started using our reading notebooks in a more meaningful manner. I began to model "during reading" responses instead of only "after reading" responses. We began to use our notebooks in a more authentic way. After workshop, we would have rich, shared discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for everyone to have the opportunity to share would have taken too long. So, instead of having one child share at a time, I started utilizing partnership and small group sharing. This worked well, but not every child had the chance to grow from the group's thinking. I wished there was a way that each child had a chance to share their thinking with the whole group. This way, the odds of receiving specific feedback that would be most beneficial would be enhanced. The more minds working together, the better.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="reading"></category><category term="ipad"></category></entry><entry><title>iPads for all</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/10/26/ipads-for-all/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-26T20:49:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-26T20:49:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-26:/2013/10/26/ipads-for-all/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/10/25/240731070/a-schools-ipad-initiative-brings-optimism-and-skepticism"&gt;A School's iPad Initiative Brings Optimism And Skepticism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of California's poorest school districts, the Coachella Valley Unified southeast of Los Angeles, is currently rolling out iPads to every student, pre-kindergarten through high school. It's an ambitious effort that administrators and parents hope will transform how kids learn, boost achievement …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/10/25/240731070/a-schools-ipad-initiative-brings-optimism-and-skepticism"&gt;A School's iPad Initiative Brings Optimism And Skepticism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of California's poorest school districts, the Coachella Valley Unified southeast of Los Angeles, is currently rolling out iPads to every student, pre-kindergarten through high school. It's an ambitious effort that administrators and parents hope will transform how kids learn, boost achievement and narrow the digital divide with wealthier districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as with tablet efforts across the country, this one faces skeptics and obstacles. Some wonder if its projected benefits are being grossly oversold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everytime I read one of these articles, the emphasis seems to dwell on the device. It's as if there exists the perfect device and every district that picks something different is doing it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concentrate on what you can do with what you have. The best camera is the one you have with you, just like it is with you and your students.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ipad"></category><category term="1to1"></category></entry><entry><title>Follow and backchannel the Apple event today</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/10/22/follow-and-backchannel-the-apple-event-today/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-22T10:26:12-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-22T10:26:12-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-22:/2013/10/22/follow-and-backchannel-the-apple-event-today/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've set up an IRC bot to feed MacRumorsLive Twitter account into the &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23eduk8me&amp;amp;uio=d4"&gt;#eduk8me IRC channel on Freenode&lt;/a&gt;. You can use the &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23eduk8me&amp;amp;uio=d4"&gt;web client&lt;/a&gt; or any IRC client to connect to the #eduk8me channel on Freenode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I'm at the Ohio ITSCO Leadership Symposium, so I don't know how much time …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've set up an IRC bot to feed MacRumorsLive Twitter account into the &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23eduk8me&amp;amp;uio=d4"&gt;#eduk8me IRC channel on Freenode&lt;/a&gt;. You can use the &lt;a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23eduk8me&amp;amp;uio=d4"&gt;web client&lt;/a&gt; or any IRC client to connect to the #eduk8me channel on Freenode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I'm at the Ohio ITSCO Leadership Symposium, so I don't know how much time I'll have to join. :-( )&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="apple"></category><category term="ipad"></category><category term="iphone"></category></entry><entry><title>iPads and reluctant writers</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/10/03/ipads-and-reluctant-writers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-03T21:27:57-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-03T21:27:57-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-03:/2013/10/03/ipads-and-reluctant-writers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mguhlin.org/2013/09/ipadifying-writing-workshop-part-1.html?m=1"&gt;Around the Corner-MGuhlin.org: iPadifying the Writing Workshop - Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of my students,” shared the 5th grade teacher whom I was interviewing for a podcast, “has trouble filling up the page. He just can’t do it. It’s too much. But, when writing on the iPad, using the …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mguhlin.org/2013/09/ipadifying-writing-workshop-part-1.html?m=1"&gt;Around the Corner-MGuhlin.org: iPadifying the Writing Workshop - Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of my students,” shared the 5th grade teacher whom I was interviewing for a podcast, “has trouble filling up the page. He just can’t do it. It’s too much. But, when writing on the iPad, using the on-screen keyboard, he can. He can type a few words at a time in the small space and pretty soon, he’s written a page. That’s amazing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a writing app called iA Writer for the iPad and iPhone/iPod touch that has a focus mode, where it only shows a few lines at a time. I wonder if that would help too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there applications for other devices that have a focus mode? (Besides iA Writer, which has a Mac version. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ipad"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Six months too young for the iPad?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/09/14/six-months-too-young-for-the-ipad/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-14T22:39:49-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-14T22:39:49-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-14:/2013/09/14/six-months-too-young-for-the-ipad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2013/09/discovering-that-your-18-month-old-is-using-an-ipad-in-pre-school/279438/"&gt;Discovering That Your 18-Month-Old Is Using an iPad in Pre-School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recent summer day in Nashville, Kara Teising opened her Facebook page for a lunchtime scroll through her timeline when she discovered a photo posted by her son’s daycare: an image of her 18-month-old son surrounded by other …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2013/09/discovering-that-your-18-month-old-is-using-an-ipad-in-pre-school/279438/"&gt;Discovering That Your 18-Month-Old Is Using an iPad in Pre-School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recent summer day in Nashville, Kara Teising opened her Facebook page for a lunchtime scroll through her timeline when she discovered a photo posted by her son’s daycare: an image of her 18-month-old son surrounded by other toddlers, their chubby faces glued to a brightly colored, animated screen of an iPad. .... After several discussions with the school’s leadership, Teising and her husband decided to pull their son out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do parents of today hold some ideology of childhood that doesn't include electronics? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shared my theory with Kirkorian –that we parents might idealize a childhood without technology as better. “I often hear ‘grown ups’ talk about the inherent value of ‘real’ objects over technology,” she said, “but frankly I don't see a difference (and there's no research to suggest there is one) between a stick and an iPad. Of course kids should have time to explore the natural environment and interact with other people. A more realistic question is whether an hour or two of touch-screens per day is going to devastate permanently cognitive/social development. It's unlikely, but we just don't know yet, and any answer will depend heavily on program content and the characteristics of individual children.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a difference between a stick and an iPad?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ipad"></category><category term="preschool"></category><category term="daycare"></category></entry><entry><title>Post Apple event 9-10-2013 notes</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/09/11/post-apple-event-9-10-2013-notes/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-11T09:46:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-11T09:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-11:/2013/09/11/post-apple-event-9-10-2013-notes/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So the latest Apple event happened. I'm always a little disappointed in them. Maybe I put my expectations too high? Anyway, for schools, the big news is the inclusion of the iWork apps (Pages, Keynote, and Numbers) and two iLife apps (iMovie and iPhoto) now available for free with new …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So the latest Apple event happened. I'm always a little disappointed in them. Maybe I put my expectations too high? Anyway, for schools, the big news is the inclusion of the iWork apps (Pages, Keynote, and Numbers) and two iLife apps (iMovie and iPhoto) now available for free with new purchases. Too bad they didn't include Garageband, but for schools looking at one to one programs with iPads this is an amazing deal. Right the start the students will have some powerful creation tools that have no equal on any other handheld or tablet device. The iPhone 5C and 5S sound pretty cool, but nothing in the "gotta have it" department. Not enough for me to update my iPhone 4 yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing else in my predictions were announced, although the iPhone 4S lives on. I'm hoping for new iPads in October, just in time for the holiday season. They'll probably be released, but will they be a good enough value against the Android tablets? I mean, the Android tablets have Minecraft too. I'm so tempted by the &lt;a href="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/p/nook-hd-plus-barnes-noble/1110060512"&gt;Barnes &amp;amp; Noble Nook HD+ Tablet&lt;/a&gt;. The screen is an amazing 1920x1280 resolution and at $149 it's half the price of an iPad mini. But then I would lose TweetBot, &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/08/07/pythonista-programming-on-your-iphone-and-ipad/"&gt;Pythonista&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/08/01/drafts-for-iphone-and-ipad-is-the-app-you-never-knew-you-needed/"&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one interesting piece in the event is the inclusion of a 64-bit processor in the iPhone 5S. There have been rumors circulating about Apple testing Macbooks Airs with ARM processors like those in the iPhones. Could the iPhone 5S be a stepping stone to these new laptops? A $499 Macbook Air with 24 hour battery life sounds pretty sweet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ios"></category><category term="ipad"></category><category term="iphone"></category><category term="apple"></category></entry><entry><title>iPhone 9-10-2013 Event Predictions</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/09/10/iphone-event-predictions/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-10T10:08:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-10T10:08:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-10:/2013/09/10/iphone-event-predictions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the latest Apple iPhone event, a time when the Internet turns to all things Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What will probably be announced&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next version of the iPhone will probably be announced, the iPhone 5S. Purported to be twice as fast as its predecessor the other redeeming feature will be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the latest Apple iPhone event, a time when the Internet turns to all things Apple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What will probably be announced&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next version of the iPhone will probably be announced, the iPhone 5S. Purported to be twice as fast as its predecessor the other redeeming feature will be the availablility of the 5S in a Champagne color. To combat the low end market for smartphones, Apple is rumored to also be coming out with the iPhone 5C. Because it will use a plastic case, it will be available in a wide range of colors. The iPhone 5, 4, and 4S will be retired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A release date for iOS 7 will also probably be announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Less likely to be announced&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A controlpad accessory for the iPhone and iPod touch to be released with iOS 7. This will allow games to take advantage of physical controls. Adding it to the AppleTV along with apps for the AppleTV could also be announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Mac Pro shipping date could be announced, but that is a long shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What will probably not be announced&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New iPads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new iPod Touch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything with computers other than the Mac Pro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iWatch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you like to see?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ios"></category><category term="iphone"></category><category term="ipad"></category></entry><entry><title>Pythonista, programming on your iPhone and iPad</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/08/07/pythonista-programming-on-your-iphone-and-ipad/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-08-07T10:42:48-04:00</published><updated>2013-08-07T10:42:48-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-08-07:/2013/08/07/pythonista-programming-on-your-iphone-and-ipad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me show you something that will make you feel young as when the world was new. -- Dr. Carol Marcus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like a teenager again while playing around with &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pythonista/id528579881?mt=8"&gt;Pythonista (Universal, $6.99)&lt;/a&gt;, an app for iOS allows you to program in python directly on the device. It reminds …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me show you something that will make you feel young as when the world was new. -- Dr. Carol Marcus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like a teenager again while playing around with &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pythonista/id528579881?mt=8"&gt;Pythonista (Universal, $6.99)&lt;/a&gt;, an app for iOS allows you to program in python directly on the device. It reminds me a lot about when I was learning to program in BASIC on my Atari 800XL (my favorite computer ever, although my iPod Touch is a close second). With Pythonista, I can finally write little apps to make my day easier. A lot nicer than going to the App store, downloading a bunch of free apps, all which have obnoxious ads and don't do quite what I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first script was written to automate my 365 project. A project that I am terrible at keeping up, but now my DOY script will make it easier when I post once a month. I always struggle with the text I add at the end of my description for the picture, where I calculate the day of the year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;#365 (218/365)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I'd end up having to go to a website to find out what the day of the year it was. Well, at least that's what I did in the past. Now I have written the following script and created a &lt;a href="http://omz-software.com/pythonista/shortcut/"&gt;shortcut to it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# We&amp;#39;re going to need work with dates, access to the clipboard,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# and to launch an app (you use the webbrowser to do that).&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;clipboard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;webbrowser&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Figure out the day of the year&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;day_of_year&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;datetime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;timetuple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;tm_yday&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Create out tag line&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;clip&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot; #365 (&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;day_of_year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;/365)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Put it in the clipboard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;clipboard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;clip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Open Camera+&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;webbrowser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;open&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;cameraplus://&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Camera+ has a shoot and share mode, which is what I have set as the default. So now I click on the DOY icon, Pythonista does its thing and Camera+ opens up. I take the picture, type my witty caption, and paste the tagline. Very, very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pythonista can also export your script as an XCode project, one that you can load into XCode and create an actual iOS app. I haven't had the chance to try that out yet. A couple of negatives. Getting scripts into Pythonista can be a lesson in patience. Due to Apple's limitations on loading code, you cannot simply load code from your Dropbox or other sources, you have to copy and paste. This also means that scripts on your iPhone are automatically synced to your iPad. There is a Dropbox workaround, but I haven't had the chance to try it out yet. The other negative that I've found so far is that there isn't a built in user interface library, so you're limited to text or creating your own graphics for things like buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it's well worth the price (especially since it's universal!).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ios"></category><category term="iphone"></category><category term="ipad"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="programming"></category><category term="pythonista"></category></entry><entry><title>Linux for 1:1 instead of Chromebooks or iPads</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/04/11/linux-for-11-instead-of-chromebooks-or-ipads/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-11T16:50:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-04-11T16:50:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-04-11:/2013/04/11/linux-for-11-instead-of-chromebooks-or-ipads/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(This post is basically me thinking out loud...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/saigonubuntulinux10.jpg"&gt;Like many districts, my district is looking at devices for a 1:1
program. The top three devices seem to be Chromebooks, iPads, Windows or
OS X laptops. Costs are the main driving factor for a lot of districts,
which basically means …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(This post is basically me thinking out loud...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/saigonubuntulinux10.jpg"&gt;Like many districts, my district is looking at devices for a 1:1
program. The top three devices seem to be Chromebooks, iPads, Windows or
OS X laptops. Costs are the main driving factor for a lot of districts,
which basically means they are choosing between Chromebooks or iPads.
While these devices have their uses, I'm wondering why we aren't looking
at Linux laptops (probably running Ubuntu). There are districts with
districts with Linux laptops, with &lt;a href="http://ubermix.org/"&gt;Ubermix&lt;/a&gt; being pretty prevalant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubermix has some neat features, the most important one is the ability
for a student to re-set their laptop on their own &lt;a href="http://ubermix.org/basics.html"&gt;with quick
recovery&lt;/a&gt;. In my mind, I'm thinking of extending this function along
with what I've learned from my &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/03/13/re-purpose-old-machines-as-chrome-browser-boxes-introducing-the-gozbrowserbox/"&gt;GozBrowserBox project&lt;/a&gt;. I would
probably use the idea of Ubermix but with a straight Ubuntu install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each laptop would be set up to use &lt;a href="https://puppetlabs.com/"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; in a serverless manner for
management and the student's home folder would be synced to a Network
Attached Storage device. The Puppet manifests would be synced and ran at
startup, and the home folder syncing would happen only at log in and log
off. Both of these to minimize any bandwidth issues. I haven't quite
figured out how to do user management. It could be done with Puppet for
1:1 managed machines, and use our current directory for shared devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup would be very, very powerful. Not only could they do
everything a Chromebook could do, but they would give the students
access to software that's not available on the web. This is a very
important consideration for students in 7th grade and lower, since most
websites limit usage by those under the age of 13. Management becomes a
non-issue with a quick recovery setup and Puppet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost per device would be between $300-$350 (without case). Comparable
Chromebooks cost $280-$310 with Google Management, and the iPad mini
starts at $329 (but can't be used with the PARCC tests, so you really
need to start at $399).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have I missed?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="1:1"></category><category term="chromebook"></category><category term="iPad"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category></entry><entry><title>Has Apple lost it?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2012/09/12/has-apple-lost-it/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-12T18:38:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-09-12T18:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2012-09-12:/2012/09/12/has-apple-lost-it/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the iPhone 5 today and updates to the iPod line. Most of
the announcements were lackluster at best, but the event laid the
groundwork for the rumored iPad mini event in October, which could be
even more disastrous than the iPhone 5 event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 5 is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the iPhone 5 today and updates to the iPod line. Most of
the announcements were lackluster at best, but the event laid the
groundwork for the rumored iPad mini event in October, which could be
even more disastrous than the iPhone 5 event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 5 is a nice upgrade, thinner and lighter, but at the same
time, it doesn’t have any feature that makes it a must upgrade for me
and my iPhone 4. This is probably more of a testimonial on how good a
phone the 4 is than what the 5 brings to the table. There are features
in the next version of iOS that I won’t be able to use, such as
turn-by-turn navigation, and, I’m assuming, Facetime over cellular, but
since there are apps I can use to replace these missing features I’m not
that worried about upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more disturbing about todays event was the iPod line refresh.
Apple now sells the iPod shuffle, iPod nano, and iPod touch (the Classic
is still available, but it hasn’t seen an update in 3 years). The iPod
shuffle makes sense as an entry level music player, and at \$49, makes
it pretty affordable. After the shuffle comes the nano, which doesn’t
make sense at all. At least the 6th generation nano had a cool look and
could be used as a watch, this 7th generation looks like an iPod touch,
works like an iPod touch, but isn’t an iPod touch. Why would Apple waste
engineering sources on the nano? They priced it at \$149, only \$50 less
than the entry level iPod touch that includes the same amount of
storage. I just can’t think of a use case where the nano makes a better
purchase than the iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the iPod touch. At the \$199 price point, they’re now
selling the 4th generation iPod touch with 16Gb instead of just 8GB. No
other changes in the now two year old device. If you want the new iPod
touch which has several of the goodies of the iPhone 5, be prepared to
shell out \$299. You do get 32Gb at this price but is it worth a third
more than the iPod touch 4th generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the pricing of the iPod touch which is the most worrisome. Making a
guess about the iPad mini launch next month, I bet that Apple will drop
the iPad 2 and put the iPad mini in at the \$399 price. This would hand
the Christmas shopping season to Amazon, Google, and possibly Barnes and
Noble. The software for iOS is heads and shoulders above what is
available for Android, but when a parent can pick up two Kindle Fire HDs
for the price of one iPad mini, what choice do you think they’re going
to make? I really doubt they’d price the iPad mini at the same price as
the new iPod touch, but let’s say they do. It would still be a third
higher than the Kindle Fire HD, although closer in price to the Nexus 7
32GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has solid devices, well built, but their pricing expectations are
all over the place. To me, it makes sense to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep the shuffle at \$49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;place the old nano form factor (but with bluetooth) with 8GB at \$99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 4th gen (8GB) (add bluetooth 4.0 and IPS screen) at \$149&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 5th gen (16GB) at \$199&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad mini (16GB) at \$299&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 2 (16GB) at \$399&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 3 (16GB) at \$499&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see more and more kids getting Kindle Fires, which is now at \$159.
Apple has dominated the tablet space (and the mobile phone space in
profits), but if they don’t price their products more aggressively, they
will lose that dominance. Right now, a \$299 iPad mini would be a tough
sell in my school district when I get get a Nexus 7 (which has better
integration with Google Drive) for \$199. Forget about a \$399 iPad
mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. Signs that Steve Jobs is gone: he would never have added that hand
strap to the iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="apple"></category><category term="iPad"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="ipodtouch"></category></entry><entry><title>A Kindle, iPad, and iPod Touch walk into a classroom - #neotech2011</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2011/03/21/a-kindle-ipad-and-ipod-touch-walk-into-a-classroom-neotech2011/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-21T18:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2011-03-21T18:12:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-03-21:/2011/03/21/a-kindle-ipad-and-ipod-touch-walk-into-a-classroom-neotech2011/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides with notes: &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/A_Kindle_iPad_and_iPod_Touch_walk_into_a_Clas.pdf"&gt;Handout&lt;/a&gt; from my presentation. For
those following along with Twitter here are the results of the poll:&lt;br&gt;
[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Twtpoll-280x300.png" title="Twtpoll"&gt;][]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the conference, and want to thank everyone that was
involved at putting it on. It was very well run (although I didn't win
the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the slides with notes: &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/A_Kindle_iPad_and_iPod_Touch_walk_into_a_Clas.pdf"&gt;Handout&lt;/a&gt; from my presentation. For
those following along with Twitter here are the results of the poll:&lt;br&gt;
[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Twtpoll-280x300.png" title="Twtpoll"&gt;][]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the conference, and want to thank everyone that was
involved at putting it on. It was very well run (although I didn't win
the MacBook Air door prize... :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Twtpoll-280x300.png" title="Twtpoll"&gt;]: http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Twtpoll.png&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="iPad"></category><category term="ipodtouch"></category><category term="kindle"></category><category term="neotech2011"></category><category term="presentations"></category></entry><entry><title>A Kindle, iPad, and iPod Touch walk into a classroom - #oetc11</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2011/02/05/a-kindle-ipad-and-ipod-touch-walk-into-a-classroom-oetc11/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-05T12:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2011-02-05T12:18:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-02-05:/2011/02/05/a-kindle-ipad-and-ipod-touch-walk-into-a-classroom-oetc11/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The slides are available on &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/present/edit?id=0AbbGU358V1WJZHc3MzYyN18zNWZydGZwNWY3&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src="http://blip.tv/play/AYKg%2B0UA" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="480" height="375" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The slides are available on &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/present/edit?id=0AbbGU358V1WJZHc3MzYyN18zNWZydGZwNWY3&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src="http://blip.tv/play/AYKg%2B0UA" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="480" height="375" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="iPad"></category><category term="ipodtouch"></category><category term="kindle"></category><category term="oetc11"></category><category term="presentation"></category></entry><entry><title>Flowchart: Should you buy an iPad?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2010/04/09/flowchart-should-you-buy-an-ipad/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-09T12:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-04-09T12:40:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-04-09:/2010/04/09/flowchart-should-you-buy-an-ipad/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked up a little flowchart in Pages on my iPad to help you make your
decision on whether you should buy one. This post and the graphic were
totally created on my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/p_1024_768_0315B0BA-2CB4-462C-84CC-F47B3E489DC3.jpeg"&gt;][]&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked up a little flowchart in Pages on my iPad to help you make your
decision on whether you should buy one. This post and the graphic were
totally created on my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/p_1024_768_0315B0BA-2CB4-462C-84CC-F47B3E489DC3.jpeg"&gt;][]&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="flowchart"></category><category term="iPad"></category></entry><entry><title>iPad initial impressions</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2010/04/07/ipad-initial-impressions/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-07T16:08:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-04-07T16:08:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-04-07:/2010/04/07/ipad-initial-impressions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are enough other reviews on the web about the iPad, so I'm going
to focus on my experiences and how I've begun to use the iPad in my home
life and how it may be used in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purchase:&lt;br&gt;
I reserved my ipad the day they opened reservations …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are enough other reviews on the web about the iPad, so I'm going
to focus on my experiences and how I've begun to use the iPad in my home
life and how it may be used in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purchase:&lt;br&gt;
I reserved my ipad the day they opened reservations on line so I would
be guaranteed to pick one up on April 3rd. I didn't trust Saturday
delivery, so I headed to Columbus to the Easton Apple Store to stand in
the "privileged line", the one which had the others who had also
reserved their iPad. When we arrived at 7:30am, there were approximately
40 people in the reserved line and about twice that many in the
"unreserved" line, those that were hoping to still pick one up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I bought mine and while my brother and sister played with iPads
in the store, I pulled out my Macbook and setup my iPad. Some reviews
talk about the iPad ready for use right out of the box, but mine popped
up the "connect to iTunes" symbol. The initial sync didn't take long,
but I really wasn't syncing up too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial Impressions:&lt;br&gt;
Fast! It is probably the fastest browsing experience that I've ever
experienced. For the first time it was the speed of the network and not
the hardware slowing me down. The onscreen keyboard isn't that bad, I'm
typing this article on it, but it does take some getting used to. The
biggest problem is keeping your fingers up off the glass so it doesn't
register additional "key" presses. The other issue is that it is
practically impossible to type without looking at the keyboard, so if
you are typing in information that is on paper, it will be a lot slower.
Im debating whether to buy the bluetooth keyboard. I paired it with my
old Think Outside keyboard, which was a piece of cake, but that keyboard
is getting old and the k and l keys do not work the best. I also bought
the Apple case for it, which helps put the iPad at a good angle to use
or type on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longer term impressions:&lt;br&gt;
There are more situations where a tablet can be used than a laptop, and
the additional screen space makes the iPad a lot more useful than the
iPod Touch. For example, at a meeting I can have the iPad in my lap or
on the table. Where the iPad shines is when I want to show others
information or something on the screen. I can just hold up the iPad or
hand it to them without the awkwardness one would experience with a
laptop. Maybe it's just the websites I visit, but lack of Flash has not
really been an issue. A lot of the video sites already support HTML 5,
which works flawlessly on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been impressed with the number of iPad ready apps already in the
app store. Some of my favorite apps, such as Evernote, WordPress, and
iSSH are already available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educational implications:&lt;br&gt;
That being said about Flash above, students would notice the inability
to use some of there favorite sites. Sites such as Starfall, which would
be amazing on the iPad, fail from lack of Flash. The availability of
Pages and Keynote bring some productivity to the iPad, but the clumsy
method of using iTunes to transfer files would hinder their use in the
classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing thoughts:&lt;br&gt;
I'm going to be posting more as I work with the device longer. I'm
excited to use it to teach a lesson in a kindergarten class to see how
well it will work as a teacher device. Some accessories will probably
end of purchasing include the camera connection kit and the Bluetooth
keyboard. The big unanswered question is "who is the iPad for?", and,
unfortunately I can't answer that yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="iPad"></category><category term="mobile"></category></entry><entry><title>The iPad has landed</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2010/04/03/the-ipad-has-landed/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-03T08:41:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-04-03T08:41:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-04-03:/2010/04/03/the-ipad-has-landed/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Braving almost 70? weather I arrived at the Easton Apple store at 7:40
am to pick up my reserved 32gb iPad. I'll have a longer review later,
but I'm currently typing this blog post while using the Wordpress app
and sitting in Cos?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, So cool.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Braving almost 70? weather I arrived at the Easton Apple store at 7:40
am to pick up my reserved 32gb iPad. I'll have a longer review later,
but I'm currently typing this blog post while using the Wordpress app
and sitting in Cos?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, So cool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="apple"></category><category term="iPad"></category></entry></feed>