<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/keynote.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2014-01-27T10:25:03-05:00</updated><entry><title>Kevin Honeycutt's Keynote #oetc14</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/01/27/kevin-honeycutts-keynote-oetc14/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-27T10:25:03-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-01-27:2014/01/27/kevin-honeycutts-keynote-oetc14/</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you want to find the best teacher in a school? Find the one that's in trouble. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I don't like laptops...I don't know what the kids in the back are doing"..."Well get up!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Why don't you give up? It's too late for them, teach the younger students. NO!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are we killing the next Steve Jobs?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"You don't learn unless you do something!"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empowerment comes from being trusted to attack learning according to your own strengths. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cereal box presenter. Amazing. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Killing education by the process of il-lamination. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kids should be sharks, not filter feeders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed action patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Coming Jobs War&lt;/em&gt; Jim Clifton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first thing we do is amputate their digital limbs at the door. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I teach kids, do you have a product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the Clovis point today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shapeways,com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maker movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/openworldproject"&gt;Open World Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ouropenworldproject.org"&gt;Our Open World Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dad, kids are going to judge this project by what they google of me. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music on iOS &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop judging kids on what they can't do. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="oetc14"></category><category term="keynote"></category></entry><entry><title>Put a countdown timer on a presentation slide</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2011/03/26/put-a-countdown-timer-on-a-presentation-slide/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-26T14:05:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-03-26:2011/03/26/put-a-countdown-timer-on-a-presentation-slide/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/countdown-300x225.png" title="countdown" /&gt;][]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past week as I was working on a presentation, I had a slide where I
asked the participants to discuss among themselves. I wanted to set a
time limit, but I didn't want to have to switch out of Keynote, I wanted
it on the slide. It took me a couple of minutes, but I finally came up
with a quite clever solution, if I do say so myself. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I needed was a little countdown video that would count
down from 10. I started a new Keynote project, and created a ten second
countdown. Originally I used ten slides, with the transition taking a
second, so that when played it would count down in ten seconds. The
problem came when I wanted to export the movie. The minimum amount of
time I could show a slide was two seconds, and since I didn't want to
count down by two a new solution had to be made. So I deleted all the
slides in my presentation save one, and put 11 text boxes on it (10-0).
I then did a pop build in and out, and set the time for the build to be
one second. The out build would happen concurrently with the in build of
the next number, so I got a pretty cool effect as a bonus. I &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Countdown.mov"&gt;exported
this out as a Quicktime movie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in my presentation, I added a question text box with a build in
transition to occur after a click. Next, I added my movie with a build
in transition to appear. The secret is to set the movie to appear
however many seconds you want to wait. I set it at 60 seconds, so
participants actually had 70 seconds until it finished. It doesn't
appear until the 60 second mark has passed, and then counts down to 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Works better than I had hoped! You can &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Countdown.mov"&gt;download the movie
here&lt;/a&gt;. (right click and use Save
as...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/countdown-300x225.png" title="countdown" /&gt;]: http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/countdown.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="keynote"></category><category term="presentations"></category></entry></feed>