<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - libraries</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/libraries.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-16T20:33:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>❂ Libraries are the future</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/10/16/libraries-are-the-future/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-16T20:33:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-16T20:33:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-16:/2013/10/16/libraries-are-the-future/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/books/2013/oct/15/neil-gaiman-future-libraries-reading-daydreaming"&gt;Neil Gaiman: Why our future depends on libraries, reading and daydreaming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was once in New York, and I listened to a talk about the building of private prisons – a huge growth industry in America. The prison industry needs to plan its future growth – how many cells are they going …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/books/2013/oct/15/neil-gaiman-future-libraries-reading-daydreaming"&gt;Neil Gaiman: Why our future depends on libraries, reading and daydreaming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was once in New York, and I listened to a talk about the building of private prisons – a huge growth industry in America. The prison industry needs to plan its future growth – how many cells are they going to need? How many prisoners are there going to be, 15 years from now? And they found they could predict it very easily, using a pretty simple algorithm, based on asking what percentage of 10 and 11-year-olds couldn't read. And certainly couldn't read for pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not one to one: you can't say that a literate society has no criminality. But there are very real correlations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting start, although the prison planning story appears to be an &lt;a href="http://www.oregonlive.com/education/index.ssf/2010/03/prisons_dont_use_reading_score.html"&gt;urban myth&lt;/a&gt; without any &lt;a href="http://jamesshelley.net/2011/12/cite-the-source/"&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But later Mr. Gaiman hits pay dirt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't think there is such a thing as a bad book for children. Every now and again it becomes fashionable among some adults to point at a subset of children's books, a genre, perhaps, or an author, and to declare them bad books, books that children should be stopped from reading. I've seen it happen over and over; Enid Blyton was declared a bad author, so was RL Stine, so were dozens of others. Comics have been decried as fostering illiteracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's tosh. It's snobbery and it's foolishness. There are no bad authors for children, that children like and want to read and seek out, because every child is different. They can find the stories they need to, and they bring themselves to stories. A hackneyed, worn-out idea isn't hackneyed and worn out to them. This is the first time the child has encountered it. Do not discourage children from reading because you feel they are reading the wrong thing. Fiction you do not like is a route to other books you may prefer. And not everyone has the same taste as you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And not just for the use of the word &lt;em&gt;tosh&lt;/em&gt;.  This needs to be shouted from the rooftops, posted in every school, said at every parent/teacher conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via: &lt;a href="http://news.slashdot.org/story/13/10/16/0212222/neil-gaiman-on-why-libraries-are-the-gates-to-the-future"&gt;Neil Gaiman On Why Libraries Are the Gates to the Future - Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="libraries"></category><category term="future"></category></entry></feed>