<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/memorization.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 22:20:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>See what happens when a father decides to do his daughter's eight grade homework</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/11/see-what-happens-when-a-father-decides-to-do-his-daughters-eight-grade-homework/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2013/10/my-daughters-homework-is-killing-me/309514/"&gt;My Daughter’s Homework Is Killing Me &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found, at both schools, that whenever I bring up the homework issue with teachers or administrators, their response is that they are required by the state to cover a certain amount of material. There are standardized tests, and everyone—students, teachers, schools—is being evaluated on those tests. I’m not interested in the debates over teaching to the test or No Child Left Behind. What I am interested in is what my daughter is doing during those nightly hours between 8 o’clock and midnight, when she finally gets to bed. During the school week, she averages three to four hours of homework a night and six and a half hours of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three or four hours of homework a night is crazy!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 22:20:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-11:2013/10/11/see-what-happens-when-a-father-decides-to-do-his-daughters-eight-grade-homework/</guid><category>homework</category><category>memorization</category></item><item><title>Let me look that up</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/01/let-me-look-that-up/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in June I road in the Great Ohio Bike Adventure (GOBA). It consists of a series of 45-6o mile bike rides over the course of a week. During our numerous downtimes, I was having a discussion with my uncle about robots and automated drivers. As we were talking, there was a point I wanted to make but I couldn't quite remember the information I wanted to use so I told him I "had to look it up". Of course, his reply was "What did you do before smartphones". It was at this moment I realized that the smartphone wasn't a crutch. If it wasn't for the smartphone, I wouldn't have know the information existed in the first place. I use my smartphone for making available to me the information that is available. &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 14:52:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-01:2013/09/01/let-me-look-that-up/</guid><category>memorization</category><category>google</category><category>search</category></item></channel></rss>