<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/mobile.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 19:54:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Formatting for the printed page is dead</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2011/09/04/formatting-for-the-printed-page-is-dead/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The PrintShop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mid 80's it seemed like the second most used program for the
Apple II was Broderbund's &lt;strong&gt;The PrintShop&lt;/strong&gt;, right after that pirated
copy of AppleWorks. For the first time, users could create posters,
cards, etc. all with fancy fonts and clip arts. As word processors and
page layout tools became more and more commonplace, the final product to
be shared was an 8 1/2" x 11" (or A4 :-)) sized sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The world is going mobile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The signs are all around us that the personal computer as we know it is
dying, to replaced with mobile technologies. Whenever I do PD,
especially with iOS devices or other portable devices, I tell the
participants that in 5 years everyone will be using portable devices
instead of computers. Unfortunately, this doesn't go over very well. The
most common concern is how will they word process. After thinking about
it, I realized what was wrong with this question. In the future you will
not be creating content that the final product will be the printed page.
You, or your students, will be creating content that will be consumed on
other mobile devices. The concept of the printed page is dying.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 19:54:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-09-04:2011/09/04/formatting-for-the-printed-page-is-dead/</guid><category>mobile</category></item><item><title>Checking out Android</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2011/01/19/checking-out-android/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As I prepare for my eTech 2011 presentation, &lt;a href="http://communities.etech.ohio.gov/planner/an-ipad-kindle-and-ipod-touch-walked-into-a-classroom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;An iPad, Kindle, and iPod
Touch walked into a classroom...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I decided that it would be
beneficial to plan on questions about Android, Android Tablets, and how
they may work in schools. The Consumer Electronics Show was held this
past week, and during it a bevy of manufacturers announced tablets, with
almost all of them running Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android is an open source operating system created at Google based on
Linux. Google allows distributes this OS free of charge to be used by
manufacturers and cellular providers on mobile devices. It competes
against other mobile operating systems such as Apple's iOS (used on the
iPhone, iPad, and iPod Touch), Microsoft Windows Phone 7, RIM Blackberry
OS, and HP's WebOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased a Motorola Droid off of eBay and received it this past week.
I've been playing around with it for the last couple of days, so this
isn't so much as a review as it is my first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;My smartphone history&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little history about my past and smartphones. I bought my first
smartphone, a Motorola Q around 2007 (I think. :-)). While it was my
first taste of online connectivity whereever I was, it was also my first
taste of, as the French would say, le pew. It was slow, ate batteries
like it was going out of style, ugly, and would just restart for now
reason. I moved on to a Samsung Omnia, then an HTC Ozone. The Ozone, at
the time (mid 2009) was Verizon's most unlocked phone. It had wifi and
the GPS was useable. All in all, not a bad phone, but still running
Windows Mobile. In August I purchased a Palm Pre Plus, which was heaven
compared to the Ozone. What holds it back is not the OS (which feels
like it could be an Apple product) but the hardware and lack of apps. As
an aside, AT&amp;amp;T does not offer service in my area, so I've gotten by with
an iPod Touch (first gen represent!) I bought in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This "First Look" will try to focus on the software itself, since in the
Android universe the quality and quantity of devices would overshadow
any comments about the hardware of the Motorola Droid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Rundown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I like:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The back button: Until I used WebOS I hadn't really thought about
    how useful a back gesture (or button) could be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Widgets: It's nice to be able to put my calendar on a screen, or a
    battery life indicator with other information about the hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of applications: So far I've been able to find an
    application for everything I need. In the market place there are
    also tons of clones of iOS games, but for the most part these are
    inferior to their iOS counterpart. Rope Cut is not Cut the Rope for
    iOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Things I don't like:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifcation bar: To open notifications you have to click and hold on
    the top bar and then drag down. Why I can't just click on the top
    bar for notifications I don't know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application switching: Unless I'm missing something, the only way to
    switch apps is to either exit back to home and click on the item or
    hold down the home key until the recently used applications show up.
    And heaven forbid you want to return to an open browser window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigation in applications: This is not consistant. Some apps, like
    imo.im (the instant messaging app I use) gives me a different menu
    depending on what screen I'm on, and to navigate to a certain screen
    may require several key presses and swipes through several other
    screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Uses in Education&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until models are released that don't require a cellular plan,
educational uses of Android are going to be limited. This year is going
to be interesting, but if you are currently researching which OS to use
in your classroom it would be hard to recommend Android until other
models are released. Android will have two big advantages over iOS
(which is going to be its biggest competitor in the upcoming year):
price and openness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools rarely look at the total operating costs of equipment and
instead focus on purchase price. The Android tablets and handhelds will
be cheaper than their iOS cousins, and in some form factors will not
have competition (the 7 inch form factor such as the Nook).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Openness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Android is Open Source, companies can release software to
automatically manage a fleet of devices. If you've been involved with
iOS app purchases, it requires several hoops to jump through, and then
it can't even automatically install the apps. This can change with
Android. Unfortunately, this will probably mean that any price savings
you received on the purchase of the devices will be eaten in the
management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Is it a contender?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, Android is a contender in the mobile space. I believe that it is a
credible threat to the iPad/iPod Touch dominance we see in schools
today. Should you wait? No. If you are looking at implementing a mobile
device initiative then don't wait for Android devices. From an
educational point of view there isn't anything that can be done on one
that can't be done on the other. The Android app store seems to be
thriving, and as more devices are sold it will only entice more
developers. Mobile devices are set to overtake personal computers &lt;a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2010/08/11/the-great-game-mobile-devices-overtaking-pcs/"&gt;any
day now&lt;/a&gt; :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What device do you use a majority of the time?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-01-19:2011/01/19/checking-out-android/</guid><category>android</category><category>cellphones</category><category>ios</category><category>mobile</category></item><item><title>iPad initial impressions</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2010/04/07/ipad-initial-impressions/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There are enough other reviews on the web about the iPad, so I'm going
to focus on my experiences and how I've begun to use the iPad in my home
life and how it may be used in education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purchase:&lt;br /&gt;
I reserved my ipad the day they opened reservations on line so I would
be guaranteed to pick one up on April 3rd. I didn't trust Saturday
delivery, so I headed to Columbus to the Easton Apple Store to stand in
the "privileged line", the one which had the others who had also
reserved their iPad. When we arrived at 7:30am, there were approximately
40 people in the reserved line and about twice that many in the
"unreserved" line, those that were hoping to still pick one up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I bought mine and while my brother and sister played with iPads
in the store, I pulled out my Macbook and setup my iPad. Some reviews
talk about the iPad ready for use right out of the box, but mine popped
up the "connect to iTunes" symbol. The initial sync didn't take long,
but I really wasn't syncing up too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial Impressions:&lt;br /&gt;
Fast! It is probably the fastest browsing experience that I've ever
experienced. For the first time it was the speed of the network and not
the hardware slowing me down. The onscreen keyboard isn't that bad, I'm
typing this article on it, but it does take some getting used to. The
biggest problem is keeping your fingers up off the glass so it doesn't
register additional "key" presses. The other issue is that it is
practically impossible to type without looking at the keyboard, so if
you are typing in information that is on paper, it will be a lot slower.
Im debating whether to buy the bluetooth keyboard. I paired it with my
old Think Outside keyboard, which was a piece of cake, but that keyboard
is getting old and the k and l keys do not work the best. I also bought
the Apple case for it, which helps put the iPad at a good angle to use
or type on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longer term impressions:&lt;br /&gt;
There are more situations where a tablet can be used than a laptop, and
the additional screen space makes the iPad a lot more useful than the
iPod Touch. For example, at a meeting I can have the iPad in my lap or
on the table. Where the iPad shines is when I want to show others
information or something on the screen. I can just hold up the iPad or
hand it to them without the awkwardness one would experience with a
laptop. Maybe it's just the websites I visit, but lack of Flash has not
really been an issue. A lot of the video sites already support HTML 5,
which works flawlessly on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been impressed with the number of iPad ready apps already in the
app store. Some of my favorite apps, such as Evernote, WordPress, and
iSSH are already available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educational implications:&lt;br /&gt;
That being said about Flash above, students would notice the inability
to use some of there favorite sites. Sites such as Starfall, which would
be amazing on the iPad, fail from lack of Flash. The availability of
Pages and Keynote bring some productivity to the iPad, but the clumsy
method of using iTunes to transfer files would hinder their use in the
classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing thoughts:&lt;br /&gt;
I'm going to be posting more as I work with the device longer. I'm
excited to use it to teach a lesson in a kindergarten class to see how
well it will work as a teacher device. Some accessories will probably
end of purchasing include the camera connection kit and the Bluetooth
keyboard. The big unanswered question is "who is the iPad for?", and,
unfortunately I can't answer that yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 16:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-04-07:2010/04/07/ipad-initial-impressions/</guid><category>iPad</category><category>mobile</category></item></channel></rss>