<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/newyear.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 15:48:50 -0500</lastBuildDate><item><title>Don't wait for the New Year</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/12/31/dont-wait-for-the-new-year/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It's the last day of the year, when a lot of people contemplate the previous year. This is also the time when many start planning on new beginnings in the new year. I say, why do we wait? Shouldn't we be planning on new beginnings throughout the year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many times when starting new initiatives at school we have this urge to wait until natural breaks, such as the start of a new school year. It feels totally natural in a school setting since we have such distinct starts and stops, unlike a lot of occupations. After college I worked a couple of years at a computer store and bank. It was weird not have such breaks. To start something new, you set the date as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this doesn't happen nearly enough in a school setting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came here tonight because when you realize you want to spend the rest of your life with somebody, you want the rest of your life to start as soon as possible. --Harry (When Harry Met Sally)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I want to incorporate something new, I want it to start as soon as possible. Don't make me wait for some arbitrary date just because we've always done it that way. I want the rest of my life start as soon as possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year everybody!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 15:48:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-12-31:2013/12/31/dont-wait-for-the-new-year/</guid><category>newyear</category></item></channel></rss>