<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - programmer</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/programmer.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-15T20:31:48-04:00</updated><entry><title>The first woman programmer, Ada Lovelace</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/10/15/the-first-woman-programmer-ada-lovelace/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-15T20:31:48-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-15T20:31:48-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-15:/2013/10/15/the-first-woman-programmer-ada-lovelace/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://programming.oreilly.com/2013/10/ada-lovelace-an-indirect-and-reciprocal-influence.html"&gt;Ada Lovelace, an Indirect and Reciprocal Influence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I heard that Ada Lovelace Day was coming, I questioned myself, “What do I actually know about Ada Lovelace?” The sum total of my knowledge: Ada was the first woman programmer and the Department of Defense honored her contributions to computation in …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://programming.oreilly.com/2013/10/ada-lovelace-an-indirect-and-reciprocal-influence.html"&gt;Ada Lovelace, an Indirect and Reciprocal Influence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I heard that Ada Lovelace Day was coming, I questioned myself, “What do I actually know about Ada Lovelace?” The sum total of my knowledge: Ada was the first woman programmer and the Department of Defense honored her contributions to computation in 1979 by naming its common programming language Ada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few Ada biographies later, I know Augusta Ada Lovelace to be an incredibly complex woman with a painful life story, one in which math, shame, and illness were continuously resurfacing themes. Despite all, Ada tirelessly pursued her passion for mathematics, making her contributions to computing undeniable and her genius all the more clear. Her accomplishments continue to serve as an inspiration to women throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm always fascinated by what some people have gone through to succeed, especially when I'm dealing with minor complaints such as "it won't print". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via: &lt;a href="http://m.slashdot.org/story/192981"&gt;Slashdot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="programmer"></category></entry></feed>