<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - progress</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/progress.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-07T10:44:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Quotes about progress</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/10/07/quotes-about-progress/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-07T10:44:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-07T10:44:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-07:/2013/10/07/quotes-about-progress/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I am working on our district's 1:1 plan, I have come across several quotes about progress that I liked (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If There Is No Struggle, There Is No Progress" -- Frederick Douglass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Don't be pushed by your problems. Be led by your dreams." -- Ralph Waldo Emerson …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I am working on our district's 1:1 plan, I have come across several quotes about progress that I liked (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If There Is No Struggle, There Is No Progress" -- Frederick Douglass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Don't be pushed by your problems. Be led by your dreams." -- Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There are many ways of going forward, but only one way of standing still." -- Franklin D. Roosevelt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Progress is impossible without change, and those who cannot change their minds cannot change anything." -- George Bernard Shaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Without deviation from the norm, progress is not possible." -- Frank Zappa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Never confuse movement with action." -- Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Those who do not move, do not notice their chains." -- Rosa Luxemburg&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="quotes"></category><category term="progress"></category></entry><entry><title>Progress breeds complexity</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/09/26/progress-breeds-complexity/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-26T20:07:13-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-26T20:07:13-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-26:/2013/09/26/progress-breeds-complexity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upon reflection of my post from yesterday, I started thinking that I was being too harsh. The problems with technology becoming too difficult to use stems more from us wanting to do more with them than the year before. Look at the evolution of the iPhone. When it was released …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Upon reflection of my post from yesterday, I started thinking that I was being too harsh. The problems with technology becoming too difficult to use stems more from us wanting to do more with them than the year before. Look at the evolution of the iPhone. When it was released, there was no App Store, no cut and paste, no backgrounding. Apple has added those features over the last 6 years, at the expense of ease of use. Now users have to create and manage an Apple ID to use the App Store and learn how cut and paste works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers 30 years ago didn't have to network or support multiple users. Printers came with a printer driver for your various applications, not for the OS. Just because Lotus 123 was able to print didn't mean that WordPerfect was going to be able to print. Applications only ran one at a time. Now your computer operating system supports networking, printing and multiple users. Applications can run at the same time. With this progress brings complexity. Users have to know how to access networked resources and to manage users. They have to know how to navigate multiple applications running at the same time. In the 80s we had &lt;a href="http://www.magee.com/magee/Automenu.htm"&gt;Automenu&lt;/a&gt; and we liked it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are victims of our own success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="progress"></category><category term="techliteracy"></category></entry></feed>