<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - raspberrypi</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/raspberrypi.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2016-01-27T09:52:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Set your Raspberry Pi up for Wifi roaming</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2016/01/27/set-your-raspberry-pi-up-for-wifi-roaming/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-27T09:52:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-01-27T09:52:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-01-27:/2016/01/27/set-your-raspberry-pi-up-for-wifi-roaming/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had a Raspberry Pi 2 just sitting around for several months, waiting for a purpose. Since I haven't come up with a purpose, I decided to make it a portable headless Linux box that will travel with me, connect to Wifi automatically, and eventually, hopefully, set it up as …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've had a Raspberry Pi 2 just sitting around for several months, waiting for a purpose. Since I haven't come up with a purpose, I decided to make it a portable headless Linux box that will travel with me, connect to Wifi automatically, and eventually, hopefully, set it up as a &lt;a href="https://piratebox.cc/"&gt;Piratebox&lt;/a&gt;. First things first, lets get it connecting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was easier than I thought it was going to be to set it to automatically connect. Basically, I modified /etc/network/interfaces to add a roam configuration for wpa supplicant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# Include files from /etc/network/interfaces.d:
source-directory /etc/network/interfaces.d

auto lo
iface lo inet loopback

iface eth0 inet manual

allow-hotplug wlan0
iface wlan0 inet manual
    # wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf
    wpa-roam /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_roam.conf

allow-hotplug wlan1
iface wlan1 inet manual
    #wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf
    wpa-roam /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_roam.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I just added the two lines that start with wpa-roam and commented out the default wpa_supplicant.conf lines. Next up was to create the &lt;code&gt;/etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_roam.conf&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;ctrl_interface=DIR=/var/run/wpa_supplicant GROUP=netdev
update_config=1
network={
        ssid=&amp;quot;home&amp;quot;
        key_mgmt=NONE
}
network={
        ssid=&amp;quot;iPhoneHotSpot&amp;quot;
        key_mgmt=WPA-PSK
        psk=&amp;quot;PASSWORD&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Adjust the parameters for your networks. Plugging the Pi into the network and manually running &lt;code&gt;sudo ifdown wlan0;sudo ifup wlan0&lt;/code&gt; is how I tested it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the pi needs to see if it doesn't have a network connection, and if it doesn't, bring wlan0 and then back up and see if it will connect. My wifi dongle (the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B003MTTJOY"&gt;Edimax EW-7811Un&lt;/a&gt;) is on wlan0, so you may need to modify. I set a crontab (&lt;code&gt;sudo crontab -e&lt;/code&gt;) with the following line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;* * * * * /bin/ping -q -c2 8.8.8.8 || (/sbin/ifdown --force wlan0 ;/sbin/ifup wlan0 )
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Every minute the Pi will send out two pings to Google's DNS servers, and if it doesn't get a reply, it will take the connection down and bring it back up. Now I have a Pi that will autoconnect to wifi. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pi"></category><category term="raspberrypi"></category><category term="wifi"></category></entry><entry><title>The little computer that could</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/10/10/the-little-computer-that-could/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-10T20:35:12-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-10T20:35:12-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-10:/2013/10/10/the-little-computer-that-could/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/oct/08/raspberry-pi-computer-million-made-in-britain-milestone"&gt;Raspberry Pi: one million units made in Britain landmark passed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi started life as an idea to bring computing in schools back to the era of the BBC Micro in the early 1980s, which inspired children to learn how a computer worked and allowed them to discover what …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/oct/08/raspberry-pi-computer-million-made-in-britain-milestone"&gt;Raspberry Pi: one million units made in Britain landmark passed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi started life as an idea to bring computing in schools back to the era of the BBC Micro in the early 1980s, which inspired children to learn how a computer worked and allowed them to discover what was possible through learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What was needed was a return to an exciting, programmable machine like the old BBC Micro; and it had to be affordable, say around £20, so every child could potentially have one," explained Eben Upton co-founder of the Raspberry Pi at its launch. "Computing wasn't being seen as the exciting, vibrant subject it should be at school – it had become lacklustre and even boring."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been studying how we could use the Raspberry Pi in out classrooms. The lack of monitors with DVI or HDMI connectors have been a stumbling block, along with the lack of Flash and mediocre performance as a desktop. Although, that's not the role the Raspberry Pi was designed to fill, it would be a good entry into the classroom. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="raspberrypi"></category></entry></feed>