<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - retrocomputing</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/retrocomputing.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Bringing my Apple Macintosh SE/30 back to life</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-05:/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago an Apple Macintosh SE/30 came across eBay at a price I was willing to pay. It had a dead hard drive in it, but that wasn't a big deal to me. I had already been looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD devices&lt;/a&gt; so the plan was to use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago an Apple Macintosh SE/30 came across eBay at a price I was willing to pay. It had a dead hard drive in it, but that wasn't a big deal to me. I had already been looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD devices&lt;/a&gt; so the plan was to use one for the drive. Old hard drives are way too loud anyway. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I finally unwrapped the beast. The Apple Extended Keyboard II appears to have sustained some damage in shipment, but I think it still works. I cracked open the case and put the SCSI2SD device in place, but after Apple HD Setup chewed on the drive for 20 minutes, it said initialization failed. Ugh. Searching the Internet brought up something called Lido, so that's what I'm going to try next. Unfortunately, I don't know how I'm going to do it on the SE/30 because I only System 6 on a floppy, so I'm going to attempt to set it up from my 20th Anniversary Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="macintosh"></category><category term="retrocomputing"></category><category term="se30"></category></entry></feed>