<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - se30</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/se30.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2016-02-06T09:45:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>The Macintosh SE/30 lives</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/06/the-macintosh-se30-lives/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-06T09:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-06T09:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-06:/2016/02/06/the-macintosh-se30-lives/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after just a little bit of tinkering, was a good night for my Macintosh SE/30. After I swapped the 2GB SD card in the SCSI2SD drive with a 256MB SD card, I was able to initialize the drive correctly. At first it only set up a 16MB partition …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after just a little bit of tinkering, was a good night for my Macintosh SE/30. After I swapped the 2GB SD card in the SCSI2SD drive with a 256MB SD card, I was able to initialize the drive correctly. At first it only set up a 16MB partition, so I did have to re-partition the drive, but after that, the installation of System 6.0.7 was a breeze. And even though this thing only has 2MB of RAM, it is quick! I don't know if it's the SCSI2SD device or the fact that System 6 doesn't require a whole lot, but Microsoft Word 4.0 loads almost instantly. I'll have to measure the boot time when I get a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Macintosh SE/30" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/pics/2016/gozse30-s.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this blog post in Microsoft Word on the SE/30. The worst part is the fact that the keyboard needs a good cleaning. I'm not too impressed with the Apple Extended Keyboard II, although I've heard people rave about it. I think I have an IIgs compact keyboard around here somewhere to replace it. The smaller size fits better with the SE/30 anyway. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="macintosh"></category><category term="se30"></category></entry><entry><title>Bringing my Apple Macintosh SE/30 back to life</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-05:/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago an Apple Macintosh SE/30 came across eBay at a price I was willing to pay. It had a dead hard drive in it, but that wasn't a big deal to me. I had already been looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD devices&lt;/a&gt; so the plan was to use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago an Apple Macintosh SE/30 came across eBay at a price I was willing to pay. It had a dead hard drive in it, but that wasn't a big deal to me. I had already been looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD devices&lt;/a&gt; so the plan was to use one for the drive. Old hard drives are way too loud anyway. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I finally unwrapped the beast. The Apple Extended Keyboard II appears to have sustained some damage in shipment, but I think it still works. I cracked open the case and put the SCSI2SD device in place, but after Apple HD Setup chewed on the drive for 20 minutes, it said initialization failed. Ugh. Searching the Internet brought up something called Lido, so that's what I'm going to try next. Unfortunately, I don't know how I'm going to do it on the SE/30 because I only System 6 on a floppy, so I'm going to attempt to set it up from my 20th Anniversary Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="macintosh"></category><category term="retrocomputing"></category><category term="se30"></category></entry></feed>