<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - software</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/software.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-27T19:38:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>The Internet Archive has added the Historical Software Archive</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/10/27/the-internet-archive-has-added-the-historical-software-archive/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-27T19:38:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-27T19:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-27:/2013/10/27/the-internet-archive-has-added-the-historical-software-archive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/historicalsoftware"&gt;Historical Software Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection contains selected historically important software packages from the Internet Archive's software archives. Through the use of in-browser emulators, it is possible to try out these items and experiment with using them, without the additional burdens of installing emulator software or tracking down the programs. Many …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/historicalsoftware"&gt;Historical Software Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection contains selected historically important software packages from the Internet Archive's software archives. Through the use of in-browser emulators, it is possible to try out these items and experiment with using them, without the additional burdens of installing emulator software or tracking down the programs. Many of these software products were the first of their kind, or utilized features and approaches that have been copied or recreated on many programs since. (historic software, vintage software, antique software)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty awesome, I spent an hour reliving Lemonade Stand. There are IBM DOS apps (such as Wordstar), Atari 8-bit (Elite), and several versions of Pac-Man.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="software"></category><category term="antique"></category></entry><entry><title>Thursday 3 for May 16, 2013</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/05/16/thursday-3-for-may-16-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-16T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-05-16T17:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-05-16:/2013/05/16/thursday-3-for-may-16-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Forecast.io&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read about &lt;a href="http://forecast.io/"&gt;Forecast&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/2013/04/forecast-lines.html"&gt;Macdrifter&lt;/a&gt;. This isn't your everyday weather site. A couple of things make it unique. On the main website there is a time machine button, which allows you to look at what the weather was in the past. The other neat feature is that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Forecast.io&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read about &lt;a href="http://forecast.io/"&gt;Forecast&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.macdrifter.com/2013/04/forecast-lines.html"&gt;Macdrifter&lt;/a&gt;. This isn't your everyday weather site. A couple of things make it unique. On the main website there is a time machine button, which allows you to look at what the weather was in the past. The other neat feature is that if you visit it from an iOS device, it asks you to install it as an HTML5 app. Nice, functional and free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;IFTTT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An oldie but a goodie, &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/dashboard"&gt;If This Then That - IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; lets you automate web services. For example, I use the Pocket read it later service. I also want to keep a copy of anything sent to Pocket just in case something happens to Pocket, so I have an IFTTT recipe that saves to Dropbox anything that I Pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;f.lux - Better lighting... for your computer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stereopsis.com/flux/"&gt;f.lux&lt;/a&gt; changes the &lt;em&gt;whiteness&lt;/em&gt; of your computer after sunset, giving it a yellowish hue. This is more pleasing to the eye in the dark and could help you sleep. Availble for Mac, Windows, Linux and jailbroken iOS devices.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="software"></category><category term="weather"></category><category term="f.lux"></category><category term="ifttt"></category></entry><entry><title>Goodreader app now supports annotating PDFs</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2010/10/03/goodreader-app-now-supports-annotating-pdfs/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-03T10:15:00-04:00</published><updated>2010-10-03T10:15:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2010-10-03:/2010/10/03/goodreader-app-now-supports-annotating-pdfs/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest update to the best \$.99 I've ever spent on an all for my
iPad just made the application even better. Goodreader now allows you to
mark up PDFs, adding notes, highlighting text, or drawing. It can save
the markup in the same file or make a copy for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest update to the best \$.99 I've ever spent on an all for my
iPad just made the application even better. Goodreader now allows you to
mark up PDFs, adding notes, highlighting text, or drawing. It can save
the markup in the same file or make a copy for you, preserving the
original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have \$1 and an iPad, this app is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="app"></category><category term="ios"></category><category term="software"></category></entry></feed>