<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/technology.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:27:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Just like cameras, the best technology is what you have</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/04/just-like-cameras-the-best-technology-is-what-you-have/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/national/education/the-best-technology-the-one-you-already-have/article14639216/"&gt;MOOCs don't benefit developing countries. Phones do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parachuting in the ‘latest and greatest’ device or gadget may have strong political appeal, and fatten the bottom lines of certain firms, and may possibly even be effective in some cases, but it may be useful to ask, How can we innovate using what we already have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat teachers like the problem … and they will be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some great snippets on integrating technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 19:27:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-04:2013/10/04/just-like-cameras-the-best-technology-is-what-you-have/</guid><category>technology</category></item><item><title>Computers are to difficult to use and I'm proud of my digital illiteracy</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/25/computers-are-to-difficult-to-use-and-im-proud-of-my-digital-illiteracy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://studiotendra.com/2013/08/14/computers-are-both-too-difficult-and-people-are-computer-illiterate/"&gt;Computers are too difficult and people are computer illiterate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adults have worn their computer illiteracy as a badge of pride for many years now so it shouldn't surprise anyone that their children share their digital inadequacies. Moreover, neither group is even willing to try to solve a problem when they encounter it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As recent privacy and malware issues have demonstrated, there is a price to be paid for computer illiteracy. And nobody should ever be proud of being ignorant. If not knowing something is a nonissue, then it's a nonissue, but don't brag about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm seeing this more and more, people expect to be spoon fed and once you get to the third step, they believe it's too hard to do and shut down.  Are you seeing this in your district?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via: &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2013/09/24/computers-are-too-difficult"&gt;Daring Fireball Linked List: Computers Are Too Difficult and People Are Computer Illiterate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 20:55:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-25:2013/09/25/computers-are-to-difficult-to-use-and-im-proud-of-my-digital-illiteracy/</guid><category>literacy</category><category>technology</category></item><item><title>Another vision of education in the future</title><link>http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/07/another-vision-of-education-in-the-future/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.edtechmagazine.com/higher/article/2013/08/map-education-technology-through-2040-infographic"&gt;An Infographic on the future of education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future is about access, anywhere learning and collaboration, both locally and globally. Teaching and learning is going to be social. Schools of the future could have a traditional cohort of students, as well as online only students who live across the country or even the world. Things are already starting to move this way with the emergence of massive open online courses (MOOCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the future of technology in education is the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infographic is much better than the article linked in the post to the Guardian. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the near future, native apps are going to become more and more prevalent. That's why Google is putting &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/native-client/"&gt;Native Client&lt;/a&gt; inside of Chrome. And the cloud will be less and less important until cellular companies loosen up the bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. And interactive whiteboards end in 2012...&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">mr.rcollins</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 22:26:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-07:2013/09/07/another-vision-of-education-in-the-future/</guid><category>future</category><category>edtech</category><category>technology</category></item></channel></rss>