<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/tlah.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2014-04-22T09:46:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Teach like a hacker - Atari version from #neotech2014</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/04/22/teach-like-a-hacker-atari-version-from-neotech2014/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-22T09:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-04-22:2014/04/22/teach-like-a-hacker-atari-version-from-neotech2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I forgot to upload my presentation from the Neotech 2014 conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls style="width:640px;height:360px;"&gt;
&lt;source src="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/neotech-tlah.webm" type='video/webm;codecs="vp8, vorbis"'/&gt;
&lt;source src="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/neotech-tlah.mp4" type='video/mp4;codecs="avc1.42E01E, mp4a.40.2"'/&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;</summary><category term="neotech2014"></category><category term="tlah"></category></entry><entry><title>Teach Like a Hacker presentation at #l21conf</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/03/12/teach-like-a-hacker-presentation-at-l21conf/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-12T21:08:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-03-12:2014/03/12/teach-like-a-hacker-presentation-at-l21conf/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is my presentation from the Learn 21 Conference today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls style="width:640px;height:360px;"&gt;
&lt;source src="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/l21-tlah.webm" type='video/webm;codecs="vp8, vorbis"'/&gt;
&lt;source src="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/l21-tlah.mp4" type='video/mp4;codecs="avc1.42E01E, mp4a.40.2"'/&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category><category term="learn21"></category></entry><entry><title>Beaver Local waiver day #bltlap</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/02/28/beaver-local-waiver-day/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-28T20:58:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-02-28:2014/02/28/beaver-local-waiver-day/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img
src='http://cdn.ryancollins.org/pics/2014/BeaverLocal-presenting.jpg'
width=200 align=right&gt;On Wednesday I had the distinct pleasure of
attending Beaver Local's professional development waiver day. It was a
twofer for me, I not only got a chance to see how they ran their waiver
day PD, but I also had the
chance to present and converse with the staff in the district. This was
invaluable to me, and I was very appreciative to have the chance to
attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Ohio eTech Conference I've been trying to screencast everytime
I teach or present. Here are the 5 presentions from Wednesday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/tlah01.mp4"&gt;Teach Like a Hacker session 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/tlah02.mp4"&gt;Teach Like a Hacker session 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/inbox01.mp4"&gt;Your inbox is not an organizational tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/dp01.mp4"&gt;Digital Publishing Session 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cdn.ryancollins.org/movies/2014/dp02.mp4"&gt;Digital Publishing Session 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My apologizes for all the recycled jokes throughout the day. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. Picture courtesy of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Ericlowe21/status/438682163622715392/photo/1"&gt;Eric Lowe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category><category term="gmail"></category><category term="dp"></category></entry><entry><title>Teach Like a Hacker presentation at #oetc14</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2014/01/31/teach-like-a-hacker-presentation-at-oetc14/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-31T18:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2014-01-31:2014/01/31/teach-like-a-hacker-presentation-at-oetc14/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm finally getting a chance to post my presentation and supplemental materials from the OETC14 conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dl.ryancollins.org/TLaH.pdf"&gt;Presentation Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dl.ryancollins.org/JEJ-RyanIs.mp3"&gt;"Ryan is a hottie" .mp3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dl.ryancollins.org/JEJ-RyanIs.m4r"&gt;"Ryan is a hottie" .m4r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dl.ryancollins.org/tlahoetc14.log.html"&gt;Backchannel log&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know, for all the flack I get about trying to promote IRC, the back channel log is the most dialogue I've ever seen happen in a session! :-)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category><category term="oetc14"></category></entry><entry><title>Learn HTML with Mozilla Thimble</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/11/01/learn-html-with-mozilla-thimble/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-01T17:49:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-11-01:2013/11/01/learn-html-with-mozilla-thimble/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although learning html has fallen out of fashion in recent years, I believe it is a skill that is important to know. Even if you'll never be a professional web developer, there are times when knowing a little html is beneficial. Today I stumbled across &lt;a href="https://thimble.webmaker.org/"&gt;Mozilla Thimble&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/mozillathimble.jpg" width=450&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It allows you to write html online in the left pain and immediately see the results in the right pane. Once you have completed your masterpiece you can post the page publicly and share the link for all to bask in your gloriousness. What's more, your masterpiece is available for others to use as a learning tool and remix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thimble is a part of &lt;a href="https://webmaker.org/"&gt;Mozilla Webmaker&lt;/a&gt; a "global community dedicated to teaching digital skills and web literacy." If you don't know where to start, they have a ton of various projects that you can load directly into Thimble and use to learn html.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="html"></category><category term="coder"></category><category term="tlah"></category></entry><entry><title>#OhioITSCO Leadership Symposium - Teach Like a Hacker</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/22/ohioitsco-leadership-symposium-teach-like-a-hacker/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-22T17:30:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-22:2013/10/22/ohioitsco-leadership-symposium-teach-like-a-hacker/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Why hack?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach like a hacker is the epitome of "work smarter, not harder". Figure out clever solutions to tough problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Coding&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using functions in spreadsheets (&lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/tag/clss/"&gt;Managing your class list in a spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.codecademy.com/dashboard"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt; (Check out the courses on Ruby and Python)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://scratch.mit.edu/"&gt;Scratch - Imagine, Program, Share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive fiction&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.inklestudios.com/inklewriter"&gt;inkle » inklewriter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://inform7.com/"&gt;Home : Inform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Examples in the classroom&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students can write programs to solve the type of problems being studied in Math. For example, write a program in your favorite language (spreadsheet, Ruby, Python, etc.) that can add fractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;English Language Arts and Social Studies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use interactive fiction to put your students into the mindset  characters in literature or in history. &lt;a href="http://www.inklestudios.com/inklewriter"&gt;Inklewriter&lt;/a&gt; can be used as a starting point, advanced students can move to &lt;a href="http://inform7.com/"&gt;Inform&lt;/a&gt;. Both can be published on the web for others to play. (Inform can be hosted in Google Drive.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this year's Nobel Prize in Chemistry, the three scientests used computers to model molecules and reactions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a news release explained it, “Chemists used to create models of molecules using plastic balls and sticks,” but “today the modeling is carried out in computers,” thanks in part to work done in the 1970s by the three new laureates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of modeling of processes can now happen in the computer, and the students can modify the model to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category></entry><entry><title>#tlah Managing your class list in a spreadsheet, part 2</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/17/tlah-managing-your-class-list-in-a-spreadsheet-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-17T10:10:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-17:2013/10/17/tlah-managing-your-class-list-in-a-spreadsheet-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we last visited our spread sheet, we used formulas to cut apart a list of names in our class that resulted in the following spreadsheet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Our great class" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/Classlistpart1final-l.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we will learn some more programming techniques in our quest to create another column in our spreadsheet which would have the students full name in the format &lt;strong&gt;Firstname Lastname&lt;/strong&gt;. To create this full name column, you might try:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=B2+C2
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ugh, what's this &lt;code&gt;#VALUE!&lt;/code&gt; result? In this instance, it is because you tried to use the &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; operand on data which cannot be added. This means we need to talk about data types. We'll touch on two today, &lt;code&gt;number&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt; (for those that know, a number data type can be a very complex beast, but we're trying to keep it simple!). A number data type is basically anything numeric. &lt;code&gt;19&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;87&lt;/code&gt; are two numbers.  We can add those two numbers and get &lt;code&gt;106&lt;/code&gt;. A string is a data type that can encompass letters, numbers, and symbols. &lt;code&gt;Luke&lt;/code&gt; is a string as is &lt;code&gt;I am your father&lt;/code&gt;. But, &lt;code&gt;19&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;87&lt;/code&gt; can also be strings, it just depends on what you want to do with them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With strings, you don't add, you concatenate (yes, that's a real word, go look it up!). When you concatenate &lt;code&gt;Luke&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;I am your father&lt;/code&gt; you get &lt;code&gt;LukeI am your father&lt;/code&gt; (no space between &lt;code&gt;Luke&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;I&lt;/code&gt; because the original strings don't have a space).  You can also concatenate &lt;code&gt;19&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;87&lt;/code&gt; to get &lt;code&gt;1987&lt;/code&gt;. The operand to concatenate is &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;. So for our example in Column D we will use the &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt; to concatenate the two fields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=B2&amp;amp;C2
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Oh, so close! But now we have &lt;code&gt;LukeSkywalker&lt;/code&gt;, we want a space between them. To add the space, we just concatenate a &lt;code&gt;" "&lt;/code&gt; in between the two cell references:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=B2&amp;amp;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;&amp;amp;C2
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And violà! We have a new column with the users &lt;code&gt;Firstname Lastname&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mygreatclass-firstname-lastname-l.png (640×292)" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/mygreatclass-firstname-lastname-l.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you write the formula to create a username which consists of the last two digits of the grad year, last name, firstname?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/tag/clss/"&gt;All posts in the series - Managing your class list in a spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category><category term="clss"></category></entry><entry><title>Command line tool for Twitter</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/29/command-line-tool-for-twitter/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-29T23:19:15-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-29:2013/09/29/command-line-tool-for-twitter/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sferik/t"&gt;sferik/t · GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A command-line power tool for Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLI takes syntactic cues from the Twitter SMS commands, however it offers vastly more commands and capabilities than are available via SMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href="http://www.floodgap.com/software/ttytter/"&gt;TTYtter: an interactive console text-based command-line Twitter client and Perl platform (whew!)&lt;/a&gt; but t looks like it could be a pretty powerful tool in scripts. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="twitter"></category><category term="cli"></category><category term="tlah"></category></entry><entry><title>#tlah Pancake hacking</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/22/tlah-pancake-hacking/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-22T15:04:02-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-22:2013/09/22/tlah-pancake-hacking/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last night we stayed at a Holiday Inn Express which offers a continental breakfast. My 9 year old daughter was fascinated with the automatic pancake maker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pancake Maker" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/pancakemaker-l.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple as can be, press &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; and less than a minute later a pancake pops out. I was curious. What if I wanted more than one? As the maker worked its magic, I noticed it said &lt;em&gt;Making pancake 01 of 01&lt;/em&gt;. Ok, so it must be possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examining the front of the device made it apparent that the aluminum was covering up something. After I waited for the Holiday Inn Express employee to leave, I pulled on the cover, revealing a control panel with a number pad. I hit &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; and the pancake maker came to life, working on pancake &lt;strong&gt;01 of 03&lt;/strong&gt;. Very cool. The 9 year old was, in her words, a little impressed. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category><category term="pancakes"></category></entry><entry><title>#tlah Getting started with virtualization using VirtualBox</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/18/tlah-getting-started-with-virtualization-using-virtualbox/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-18T09:55:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-18:2013/09/18/tlah-getting-started-with-virtualization-using-virtualbox/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you want to check out Linux on your current machine safely, leaving your current set up untouched? Virtualization allows you to do this using &lt;a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/"&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;. We are investigating this method to &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/08/28/solve-byod-consistency-issues-with-virtualbox/"&gt;integrate BYOD with our 1 to 1 program&lt;/a&gt;. Wikihow has a nice &lt;a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Install-Ubuntu-on-VirtualBox"&gt;write up on how to install Ubuntu on VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;. Keep in mind that you want to have at least 2GB of memory (4 would be better) and 10-20GB of disk space free. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have it set up, play around with Ubuntu and see what all the fuss is about!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="virtualization"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="tlah"></category></entry><entry><title>#tlah Managing your class list in a spreadsheet, part 1</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/13/tlah-managing-your-class-list-in-a-spreadsheet-part-1/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-13T10:47:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-13:2013/09/13/tlah-managing-your-class-list-in-a-spreadsheet-part-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You have a class list, or several, and you need to manage those names. Your principal may need a list for various reasons, or you may want to email all the students in your class, or you may want to import your students into a new web service that you'd like to use. Now you could manage the list manually, creating the different formats one  student at a time. Or you could teach like a hacker and let a spreadsheet do all the hard work. My examples are going to use Google Sheets, but the concepts are the same in almost every spreadsheet. It's been awhile since I've used AppleWorks on an Apple //e, so I don't know how well these steps would work there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be assuming basic knowledge of spreadsheets in this tutorial. You'll need to know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rows are labeled with numbers starting with 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Columns are labeled with letters starting with A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cells are referenced just like in the game Battleship. Cell &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt; is in the first column, second row down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to assume you can use copy and paste to highlight your class list in your student information system software, copy, and paste it into a spreadsheet. Lets start by creating the spreadsheet. Go to Google Drive and create a new spreadsheet. Click on &lt;strong&gt;Untitled spreadsheet&lt;/strong&gt; in the upper left and name it &lt;strong&gt;My Great Class&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="NameSpreadsheet-m.png (320×148)" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/NameSpreadsheet-m.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first row put &lt;strong&gt;Full Name&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;First Name&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Last Name&lt;/strong&gt; as column headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Column Headings-l.png (640×249)" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/Column%20Headings-l.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets make the column headings pretty. Click on the &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; in row one on the left to highlight the row. Then use the two formatting text icons to set the text color and background color. Then click the &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;old button for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pretty Columns-l.png (640×246)" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/Pretty%20Columns-l.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the class list we are going to use. You should be able to copy them from here and paste them right into the spreadsheet at cell &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Skywalker, Luke
Organa, Leia
Kenobi, Obi Wan
Vader, Darth
Solo, Han
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It's a class list alright, but now we have a problem. How do we get the last name and first name without re-typing? We are going to use a &lt;strong&gt;function&lt;/strong&gt; (sometimessometimes referred to as a &lt;strong&gt;formula&lt;/strong&gt;, depending on your software). Click in &lt;strong&gt;C2&lt;/strong&gt;. You should be to the right of &lt;em&gt;Skywalker, Luke&lt;/em&gt;.  Looking at our list, we notice that there is a &lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt; after each last name. We can use that in our function to know where our last name ends. The function in Google Sheets that we are going to use is called &lt;strong&gt;LEFT()&lt;/strong&gt;. Functions take parameters, the little pieces of information that you want the function to work with. the &lt;strong&gt;LEFT()&lt;/strong&gt; takes one mandatory parameter and one optional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;LEFT(text,number)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The mandatory parameter is &lt;em&gt;text&lt;/em&gt;, and it references the cell we will be working with. For &lt;strong&gt;Luke&lt;/strong&gt; that would be &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; parameter is how many characters to return, we'll leave it off first. You start entering a function with &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;. Let's try out the &lt;strong&gt;LEFT()&lt;/strong&gt; function. In &lt;strong&gt;C2&lt;/strong&gt; enter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=LEFT(a2)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hit enter.  Looky there, we grabbed the &lt;em&gt;S&lt;/em&gt; from Skywalker!! Parameters are separated in the function by a comma. Let's add another parameter to &lt;strong&gt;LEFT()&lt;/strong&gt;, and that is to tell it how many characters to grab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=LEFT(a2,8)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hit enter. It grabbed the first 8 characters from cell &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt;.  Now in a perfect world everyone's last name would have the same number of characters. Unfortunately, our world is much like a world a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away. We need a way to find out the character position of the &lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt;. There is another function call &lt;strong&gt;SEARCH&lt;/strong&gt;. It will search through the text of a cell and return the position of the found text. In &lt;strong&gt;C2&lt;/strong&gt; try out this function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=SEARCH(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;,A2)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After hitting enter, &lt;strong&gt;C2&lt;/strong&gt; should contain the number 10, indicating that the comma is in the 10th position. Parameters in functions can also contain other functions, so we can use the &lt;strong&gt;SEARCH()&lt;/strong&gt; function in place of the second parameter in the &lt;strong&gt;LEFT()&lt;/strong&gt; function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=LEFT(a2,SEARCH(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;,A2))
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Oh, so close!!! It's returning the comma. We can use simple arithmetic to fix this, since the comma is one character, let's subtract them in the function:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=LEFT(a2,SEARCH(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;,A2)-1)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Breaking down the second parameter, you have &lt;code&gt;SEARCH(",",A2)-1&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;SEARCH(","A2)&lt;/code&gt; is going to return the position of the comma, which we know with &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt; is 10. The &lt;code&gt;-1&lt;/code&gt; subtracts one from the answer of the search function, leaving us in this example with 9. Congratulations, you now have cut out &lt;em&gt;Skywalker&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To copy the function to the other cells you're going to want to use &lt;strong&gt;fill down&lt;/strong&gt;. Select cell &lt;strong&gt;C2&lt;/strong&gt; if it isn't already selected.  Mouse over the square in the bottom right of the cell, and the cursor turns into a crosshair. Click and drag down to cell &lt;strong&gt;C6&lt;/strong&gt;. When you let up, it will fill in the cells with your function, automatically changing the references to reflect the row. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets go to &lt;strong&gt;B2&lt;/strong&gt; and work on the first name. We can't use the left function because it always starts at position 0. But we can use the &lt;strong&gt;MID()&lt;/strong&gt; function, which takes 3 mandatory parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=MID(text,start,number)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We already know what to put in for the first two parameters. The text to find is the cell with the data, and in this case it's &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt;. The start position is found by searching for the comma and adding 2. (Why 2? Remember, there is a space after the comma.) Our function starts to look like &lt;code&gt;=MID(A2,SEARCH(",",A2)+2,number)&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Number&lt;/em&gt; is the number of characters to return. We'll have to get tricky by using a new function call &lt;strong&gt;LEN&lt;/strong&gt; which calculates the length of the whole string and subtracting the position of the &lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt;. Our final function looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;=MID(A2,SEARCH(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;,A2)+2,LEN(A2)-SEARCH(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;,A2)+2)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Feel like a hacker yet? Let's break down the three parameters in that function!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;A2&lt;/code&gt;: This is the cell with the data we want to manipulate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SEARCH(",",A2)+2&lt;/code&gt;: Find the position of the first comma and add two to skip over the comma and space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;LEN(A2)-SEARCH(",",A2)+2&lt;/code&gt;: Take the length of &lt;strong&gt;A2&lt;/strong&gt; and subtract the position of the comma then add two to skip over the comma and space. This gives us the length of the string to return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then fill down the function from &lt;strong&gt;B2&lt;/strong&gt; and it should populate your first name fields. Always, ALWAYS feel free to play around with the functions until you get them right. You should have the start of a great class list!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Classlistpart1final-l.png (640×370)" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/Classlistpart1final-l.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the next part!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category><category term="clss"></category></entry><entry><title>Teach like a hacker</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/09/12/teach-like-a-hacker/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-12T10:02:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-12:2013/09/12/teach-like-a-hacker/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's very seldom that I type a phrase into Google and get no results, but that is what a Google search for &lt;strong&gt;"Teach like a hacker"&lt;/strong&gt; returns (Bing also returns no results). Maybe it is the negative connotations that Hollywood has embedded into our culture on the term hacker that scares people away from it. I believe that the educational community should embrace &lt;em&gt;hacking&lt;/em&gt;.  Teach like a hacker does not mean going all Matthew Broderick in &lt;em&gt;Wargames&lt;/em&gt; and break into computers. I prefer the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker_(hobbyist)"&gt;Wikipedia hobbyist hacker definition&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In home and hobby circles, a hacker is a person who enjoys exploring the limits of what is possible, in a spirit of playful cleverness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of educational hacking came &lt;a href="http://www.mercurynews.com/ci_23324450/san-jose-teachers-district-agree-landmark-contract"&gt;in the San Jose teacher contract that was unified in May&lt;/a&gt;. California state law requires that teacher evaluations include standardized testing, but since "There is no reliable study showing that increase so-called accountability by making student test scores a significant part of evaluation improves outcomes for students or teacher performance" "student performance will be part of the discussion on evaluations, teachers won't be penalized if students don't meet expectations." They followed the letter of the law by doing what is best for the students of the districts, evaluating and giving the district tools to hire and retain the best teachers available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or how about using &lt;a href="https://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome"&gt;Amazon Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; to assist in grading? You could upload anonymized student work and pay someone to check for spelling and/or grammatical errors, allowing you to concentrate on the concepts. This is even easier for subjects with only one answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you used the phrase, "work smarter, not harder"? Hacking is working smarter. In simple terms, it is the act of working efficiently, allowing your students and yourself to be more effective. When I am tasked with completing something tedious, the first thing I think about is how I can automate it. Now, as you read this, you may be thinking, "Ryan, you're nuts! I don't have time to learn all this computer stuff." Hacking in the long run will save you time. It may take a little bit of time to set up, but over the long haul it pays off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Is it worth the time?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Is it worth the time" src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/is_it_worth_the_time.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That chart really is an eye opener. You can spend up to 6 days (144 hours) automating a daily task that saves you 5 minutes a day and you will still save time over 5 years. One hundred and forty four hours is equivalent to over 3 and a half 40 hour work weeks. And that's just to automate something to save 5 minutes a day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What tedious tasks would you like to automate?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tlah"></category></entry></feed>