<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/welldesigned.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-11-25T20:02:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Familiarity doesn't always mean productive or well designed</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/11/25/familiarity-doesn-t-always-mean-productive-or-well-designed/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-25T20:02:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-11-25:2013/11/25/familiarity-doesn-t-always-mean-productive-or-well-designed/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20131124/while-users-lament-only-25-percent-of-yahoos-willing-eat-mail-dogfood-memo/"&gt;Clinging to Outlook, Only 25% of Employees Willing to Use Yahoo Mail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point in your life, Outlook may be familiar, which we can often confuse with productive or well designed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times have you been faced with a change in software or hardware, and
just wish you can go back to the old way? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next sentence is just all sorts of awesome:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, we can admire the application for its survival, an anachronism of
the now defunct 90s PC era, a pre-web program written at a time when NT Server
terrorized the data center landscape with the confidence of a T-Rex born to
yuppie dinosaur parents who fully bought into the illusion of their son’s utter
uniqueness because the big-mouthed, tiny-armed monster infant could mimic the
gestures of The Itsy-Bitsy Pterodactyl. There was a similar outcry when we
moved away from Outlook’s suite-mates in the Microsoft Office dreadnaught. But
whether it’s familiarity, laziness or simple stubbornness dressed in a cloak of
Ayn Randian Objectivism, the time has come to move on, commrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="productive"></category><category term="welldesigned"></category></entry></feed>