<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - word</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feed/tag/word.atom" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-12T23:17:40-04:00</updated><entry><title>And you think you know someone who hates Microsoft Word</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2013/10/12/and-you-think-you-know-someone-who-hates-microsoft-word/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-12T23:17:40-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-12T23:17:40-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-12:/2013/10/12/and-you-think-you-know-someone-who-hates-microsoft-word/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2013/10/why-microsoft-word-must-die.html"&gt;Why Microsoft Word must Die&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate Microsoft Word. I want Microsoft Word to die. I hate Microsoft Word with a burning, fiery passion. I hate Microsoft Word the way Winston Smith hated Big Brother. Our reasons are, alarmingly, not dissimilar ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Word is a tyrant of the imagination, a …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2013/10/why-microsoft-word-must-die.html"&gt;Why Microsoft Word must Die&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate Microsoft Word. I want Microsoft Word to die. I hate Microsoft Word with a burning, fiery passion. I hate Microsoft Word the way Winston Smith hated Big Brother. Our reasons are, alarmingly, not dissimilar ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Word is a tyrant of the imagination, a petty, unimaginative, inconsistent dictator that is ill-suited to any creative writer's use. Worse: it is a near-monopolist, dominating the word processing field. Its pervasive near-monopoly status has brainwashed software developers to such an extent that few can imagine a word processing tool that exists as anything other than as a shallow imitation of the Redmond Behemoth. But what exactly is wrong with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've moved to formatting with Markdown in most of my writing, with a smattering of Google Docs. I don't remember the last time I used Word (although I do fire up LibreOffice from time to time). In a lot of businesses Word is integrated into a lot of workflows that would be hard to replace. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="word"></category></entry></feed>