<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ryancollins.org/feed/tag/writing.atom" rel="self"></link><id>http://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2013-10-03T21:27:57-04:00</updated><entry><title>iPads and reluctant writers</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/10/03/ipads-and-reluctant-writers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-03T21:27:57-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-03:2013/10/03/ipads-and-reluctant-writers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mguhlin.org/2013/09/ipadifying-writing-workshop-part-1.html?m=1"&gt;Around the Corner-MGuhlin.org: iPadifying the Writing Workshop - Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One of my students,” shared the 5th grade teacher whom I was interviewing for a podcast, “has trouble filling up the page. He just can’t do it. It’s too much. But, when writing on the iPad, using the on-screen keyboard, he can. He can type a few words at a time in the small space and pretty soon, he’s written a page. That’s amazing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a writing app called iA Writer for the iPad and iPhone/iPod touch that has a focus mode, where it only shows a few lines at a time. I wonder if that would help too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there applications for other devices that have a focus mode? (Besides iA Writer, which has a Mac version. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ipad"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Pew Research - Impact of Digital Tools on Student Writing</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/07/19/pew-research-impact-of-digital-tools-on-student-writing/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Collins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-07-19:2013/07/19/pew-research-impact-of-digital-tools-on-student-writing/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pewinternet.org/~/media//Files/Reports/2013/PIP_NWP%20Writing%20and%20Tech.pdf"&gt;The Impact of Digital Tools on Student Writing and How Writing is Taught in Schools&lt;/a&gt; is a report from the PewResearchCenter creating from surveying Advanced Placement and National Writing Project teachers. Overall, the teachers believe that digital tools have a postive benefit on student writing with some concern about informal language appearing in formal writing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="writing"></category><category term="research"></category></entry><entry><title>Distraction free writing with JDarkroom</title><link href="http://ryancollins.org/2011/01/21/distraction-free-writing-with-jdarkroom/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-21T13:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2011-01-21:2011/01/21/distraction-free-writing-with-jdarkroom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sc_1-300x240.png" title="sc_1" /&gt;][]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are several full screen text editing apps, I've settled on
&lt;a href="http://www.codealchemists.com/jdarkroom/"&gt;JDarkroom&lt;/a&gt;. Written in Java, JDarkroom is a distraction free text
editor, taking over your entire screen so you can concentrate on writing
and not worry about new email or tweets. It is patterned after &lt;a href="http://they.misled.us/dark-room"&gt;Darkroom
for Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.hogbaysoftware.com/products/writeroom"&gt;Writeroom for Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was using Evernote for writing, but it doesn't have a full screen
mode. To emulate the ability to sync my notes written in JDarkroom with
my other devices I use &lt;a href="http://db.tt/wYZUa8E"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; (Affiliate code in link,
&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com"&gt;dropbox.com&lt;/a&gt; is the website without the affiliate code). Now I just
save my notes into my Dropbox, and Dropbox takes care of syncing them
across my devices. The Dropbox app for Android allows me to edit text
files directly in the application, and there are several apps for iOS
devices that will let you do the same. For mark up in text files I use
John Gruber's &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. It's a very readable way to encode
formatting in a text file. There are several libraries that let you then
convert it to html or back to markdown. I installed the &lt;a href="http://c.hadcoleman.com/wordpress-plugins/wmd-editor-wordpress-plugin/"&gt;WMD plug in for
Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; which allows me to write in Markdown (or just copy and
paste from one of my files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's a little convoluted, and as soon as Evernote as a full screen
editor option I'll probably switch back to it, it does work for me. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img alt="" src="http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sc_1-300x240.png" title="sc_1" /&gt;]: http://ryancollins.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sc_1.png&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="editor"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry></feed>