<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - Hardware</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ryancollins.org/feed/category/hardware.atom" rel="self"></link><id>https://ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2016-02-15T15:59:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Distraction free writing tools and hardware</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/15/distraction-free-writing-tools-and-hardware/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-15T15:59:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T15:59:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-15:/2016/02/15/distraction-free-writing-tools-and-hardware/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After I stumbled across the &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/adamleeb/hemingwrite-a-distraction-free-digital-typewriter"&gt;Hemingwrite - A Distraction Free Digital Typewriter by Hemingwrite&lt;/a&gt; Kickstarter, I started looking at different ways to accomplish the same task but without spending $500 on a device. I've always had an interested in different writing setups, and would love to be a writer. For some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After I stumbled across the &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/adamleeb/hemingwrite-a-distraction-free-digital-typewriter"&gt;Hemingwrite - A Distraction Free Digital Typewriter by Hemingwrite&lt;/a&gt; Kickstarter, I started looking at different ways to accomplish the same task but without spending $500 on a device. I've always had an interested in different writing setups, and would love to be a writer. For some reason, my lack of grammar and my legendary skill at procrastination has not resulted in the next great American novel. Here are some of my setups I've been trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Macintosh SE/30 running System 6 with Microsoft Word&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/"&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2016/02/06/the-macintosh-se30-lives/"&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2016/02/07/scsi2sd-with-my-macintosh-se-30/"&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; on my Macintosh SE/30 and about bringing it back to life. It works really well as a distraction free system, it's very fast, quiet, and reliable. Pulling documents off of the machine is as simple as copying them to a floppy drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;IBM Thinkpad T51e running Ubuntu at the console and using vim&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't that bad of a machine, the keyboard is really nice. Unfortunately, I can run multiple consoles and can still chat and surf (all at the console) but it's harder to not be distracted. It's really nice in the fact that I can use Dropbox or git on it, and reconfiguring the console font gave me a pretty nice font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Atari 800 running The Last Word&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing on my Atari 800 is fun! The keyboard is really nice, and The Last Word is a fantastic word processor. Pulling files off is a little bit of a pain (saving to a disk image and then extracting the file from that disk image) and I haven't figured out a good way to send files to it for editing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Atari MegaSTe running Protext&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the keyboard on the Mega STe, but writing in Protext wasn't the best. I don't know if it was the weird interface or what, but it just wasn't a nice experience. I will probably go back to ST Writer the next time I write with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Raspberry Pi with a Nook Simple Touch display&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My newest experiment is using a Nook Simple Touch as the display. That was one feature of the Hemingwrite that I really liked, the use of an e-ink display. E-ink is the display used in the black and white e-readers,and has a very low power usage profile. The other advantage is the fact that it works well in bright light situations, such as outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this working as a prototype in my house. The Raspberry Pi is connected to my wifi, and running tmux at the console. With a rooted Nook Simple Touch, I connected to the local wifi and ran vx-connectbot which connected to my Pi. After connecting, I ran tmux -a, which then connected the vx-connectbot session with the console session, and I used the keyboard connected to the Pi but the display was on the Nook Simple Touch. I had to configure some vx-connectbot settings to get a good experience, but it worked really well. Next up is to figure out how to package the parts into something that would be portable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="distractionfree"></category></entry><entry><title>SCSI2SD with my Macintosh SE/30</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/07/scsi2sd-with-my-macintosh-se-30/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-07T19:19:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-07T19:19:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-07:/2016/02/07/scsi2sd-with-my-macintosh-se-30/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was working on my SE/30, I knew I didn't want to go with a SCSI hard drive. I started looking online and came across the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD&lt;/a&gt;. I purchased mine with a 256MB SD card from &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com/itm/SCSI2SD-3-5-includes-256MB-industrial-grade-Single-Level-Cell-microSD-card-/191783840220?hash=item2ca73529dc:g:z4AAAOSwFnFWBHDt"&gt;Inertial Computing on eBay&lt;/a&gt;. Now that it is up and running, I'm …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was working on my SE/30, I knew I didn't want to go with a SCSI hard drive. I started looking online and came across the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD&lt;/a&gt;. I purchased mine with a 256MB SD card from &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com/itm/SCSI2SD-3-5-includes-256MB-industrial-grade-Single-Level-Cell-microSD-card-/191783840220?hash=item2ca73529dc:g:z4AAAOSwFnFWBHDt"&gt;Inertial Computing on eBay&lt;/a&gt;. Now that it is up and running, I'm very happy with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using with an older Macintosh, you may have an issue when it comes to initializing and using a non-Apple drive. The first time, Apple HD SC Setup wouldn't find the drive. I then found this &lt;a href="https://68kmla.org/forums/index.php?/topic/24810-questions-about-scsi2sd-setup-in-mac-lc-iii/"&gt;forum post&lt;/a&gt;. I followed dougg3's directions when setting up the SCSI2SD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the vendor to the string " SEAGATE" (yes, there is a single space in front of SEAGATE for a total of 8 characters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the product ID to the string "          ST225N" (10 spaces in front for a total of 16 characters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the revision to the string "1.0 " (with a space after, for a total of 4 characters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple HD SC Setup then saw the drive. The other thing I had to do was re-partition the drive after it set it up, since Apple HD SC Setup only create a 16MB partition and left the rest of the drive unpartitioned. I deleted that partition and then created a 256MB partition.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="scsi"></category><category term="scis2sd"></category></entry><entry><title>The Macintosh SE/30 lives</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/06/the-macintosh-se30-lives/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-06T09:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-06T09:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-06:/2016/02/06/the-macintosh-se30-lives/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after just a little bit of tinkering, was a good night for my Macintosh SE/30. After I swapped the 2GB SD card in the SCSI2SD drive with a 256MB SD card, I was able to initialize the drive correctly. At first it only set up a 16MB partition …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight, after just a little bit of tinkering, was a good night for my Macintosh SE/30. After I swapped the 2GB SD card in the SCSI2SD drive with a 256MB SD card, I was able to initialize the drive correctly. At first it only set up a 16MB partition, so I did have to re-partition the drive, but after that, the installation of System 6.0.7 was a breeze. And even though this thing only has 2MB of RAM, it is quick! I don't know if it's the SCSI2SD device or the fact that System 6 doesn't require a whole lot, but Microsoft Word 4.0 loads almost instantly. I'll have to measure the boot time when I get a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The Macintosh SE/30" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/pics/2016/gozse30-s.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this blog post in Microsoft Word on the SE/30. The worst part is the fact that the keyboard needs a good cleaning. I'm not too impressed with the Apple Extended Keyboard II, although I've heard people rave about it. I think I have an IIgs compact keyboard around here somewhere to replace it. The smaller size fits better with the SE/30 anyway. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="macintosh"></category><category term="se30"></category></entry><entry><title>Bringing my Apple Macintosh SE/30 back to life</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-05T09:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-02-05:/2016/02/05/bringing-my-apple-macintosh-se-30-back-to-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago an Apple Macintosh SE/30 came across eBay at a price I was willing to pay. It had a dead hard drive in it, but that wasn't a big deal to me. I had already been looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD devices&lt;/a&gt; so the plan was to use …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago an Apple Macintosh SE/30 came across eBay at a price I was willing to pay. It had a dead hard drive in it, but that wasn't a big deal to me. I had already been looking at the &lt;a href="http://www.codesrc.com/mediawiki/index.php?title=SCSI2SD"&gt;SCSI2SD devices&lt;/a&gt; so the plan was to use one for the drive. Old hard drives are way too loud anyway. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I finally unwrapped the beast. The Apple Extended Keyboard II appears to have sustained some damage in shipment, but I think it still works. I cracked open the case and put the SCSI2SD device in place, but after Apple HD Setup chewed on the drive for 20 minutes, it said initialization failed. Ugh. Searching the Internet brought up something called Lido, so that's what I'm going to try next. Unfortunately, I don't know how I'm going to do it on the SE/30 because I only System 6 on a floppy, so I'm going to attempt to set it up from my 20th Anniversary Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="macintosh"></category><category term="retrocomputing"></category><category term="se30"></category></entry><entry><title>Some fun with ST Writer on the Atari MegaSTe</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2016/01/31/some-fun-with-st-writer-on-the-atari-megaste/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-01-31:/2016/01/31/some-fun-with-st-writer-on-the-atari-megaste/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a thread on &lt;a href="http://atariage.com/forums/topic/208862-word-processing-on-st-to-publish-on-windows/"&gt;AtariAge&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to write up my blog posts tonight on my Atari MegaSTe in ST Writer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Atari MegaSTe was released near the end of the Atari computer era with a 68000 cpu running at 16MHz in a case that separates the keyboard with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by a thread on &lt;a href="http://atariage.com/forums/topic/208862-word-processing-on-st-to-publish-on-windows/"&gt;AtariAge&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to write up my blog posts tonight on my Atari MegaSTe in ST Writer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Atari MegaSTe was released near the end of the Atari computer era with a 68000 cpu running at 16MHz in a case that separates the keyboard with the computer itself. I'm using the Atari SC1224 color monitor with it (12" at 640x200 resolution) which is fine for most things. The mono monitor is a superb 640x400 resolution at 70Hz, but mine needs some adjusting since the screen is too small. The keyboard is pretty amazing, one of the best feeling keyboards I have every used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ST Writer is the word processor that is the heir apparent to the AtariWriter word processor for Atari's 8-bit line of computers. I used AtariWriter for at least 6 years as my word processor, and it made the most out of the 40 character wide screen. ST Writer feels like coming home, although now with 2.5MB of free space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To post the article, I will use ZModem to transfer it to my Linux box where I can fix the line endings and can then use Pelican to post. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty weird to be back on a single processing system with limited Internet access. I should do this more often! &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="atarist"></category><category term="atari"></category><category term="stwriter"></category></entry><entry><title>What a disappointing article, tablets vs. laptops</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/12/23/what-a-disappointing-article-tablets-vs-laptops/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-23T14:24:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-12-23T14:24:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-12-23:/2013/12/23/what-a-disappointing-article-tablets-vs-laptops/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scholastic has posted a versus article, &lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/browse/article.jsp?id=3757847"&gt;Laptop Vs
Tablet&lt;/a&gt;, where Gary
Stager and Dan Brenner duel over what is the best. Both arguments are very weak.
Mr. Stager takes the old arugment that the &lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/browse/article.jsp?id=3757848"&gt;iPad is a consumption
device&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPad is a consumption device. Sure, you can use it …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scholastic has posted a versus article, &lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/browse/article.jsp?id=3757847"&gt;Laptop Vs
Tablet&lt;/a&gt;, where Gary
Stager and Dan Brenner duel over what is the best. Both arguments are very weak.
Mr. Stager takes the old arugment that the &lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/browse/article.jsp?id=3757848"&gt;iPad is a consumption
device&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPad is a consumption device. Sure, you can use it for Web browsing, video-watching, or note-taking, but the laptop affords a much greater range of expressive possibilities. Apple’s embrace of digital textbooks reinforces a quaint view of education that transfers agency from learners to publishers. The tools for creating e-books, such as iBooks Author, require Macs, but the laptop cannot read the books it creates, forcing schools to choose between textbooks and computing. Apple has made it clear that education is about content delivery and testing, no longer about the power to be your best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument is no long valid. Creation apps that I have used on my iPad include
Codea, Pythonista, iMovie, Garageband, Elements, iA Writer, Google Drive, and
QuickOffice. Instead of telling us why an iPad isn't the right tool, tell us why
a laptop is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Mr. Brenner &lt;a href="http://www.scholastic.com/browse/article.jsp?id=3757849"&gt;tells us what they do on the
iPad&lt;/a&gt;. Paperless
workflows, email, textbooks, these are some of the things they do on the
tablets. I didn't see anything in the list that you can't also do on laptops. In
fact, he ends the column with "P.S. I wrote this article on my laptop computer
at work. It seemed like the right tool for the job!".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final decision in these discussions usually boil down to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can we afford?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can we support?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What supports our teaching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did your district decide?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="featured"></category><category term="tablets"></category><category term="laptops"></category></entry><entry><title>Portable USB battery options</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/11/10/portable-usb-battery-options/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-10T15:09:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-11-10T15:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-11-10:/2013/11/10/portable-usb-battery-options/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href="http://www.scottsibberson.com/2013/11/lenmar-power-pack.html"&gt;Scott's post on the Lenmar Power Pack&lt;/a&gt; and that reminded me that I had been wanting to post my portable power options. My first USB charger was a Duracell model I picked up at Meijer on the discountinued rack several years ago. It worked ok, but since them …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href="http://www.scottsibberson.com/2013/11/lenmar-power-pack.html"&gt;Scott's post on the Lenmar Power Pack&lt;/a&gt; and that reminded me that I had been wanting to post my portable power options. My first USB charger was a Duracell model I picked up at Meijer on the discountinued rack several years ago. It worked ok, but since them I've upgraded. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up is the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B006FXUS1C"&gt;Tekkeon MP1580 TEKCHARGE Mobile Power Pack and Battery Charger&lt;/a&gt;. I bought this one because it can take regular AA batteries. I also bought an 8 pack of the Sanyo Eneloop batteries. This way I can use the charger twice before I have to find an outlet. It's also pretty compact. Unfortunately, AA batteries aren't the best way to charge an iPhone, only bringing it up 30-40%. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second is a &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B0073WV1UQ"&gt;Mophie Juice Pack&lt;/a&gt; for my iPhone. This one I almost always use anytime I know I'm not going to be near an outlet for an entire day. It will bring my phone up to about 60%. It's a little nicer than the USB chargers since I don't have to mess around with cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final device I use is the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B00AANQLRI"&gt;Jackery Giant 10400mAh Premium Portable High Capacity Dual-Port External Battery Power Bank Backup Charger&lt;/a&gt;. This thing can charge my iPhone several times and I've read that it will charge my iPad 3 once (I haven't had a chance to try that out). It is heavy though, and bulkier than the above mentioned devices. I always carry it in my bag though, and if I am going out with friends I'll grab it and a couple of cables so I can charge their phones too (although I don't have an Apple device that require a Lightning cable, so I can't charge those).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. For the Great Ohio Bike Adventure back in June I bought the &lt;a href="http://amzn.com/B00828VFT2"&gt;AGPtek 5000mAh Solar Power Dual USB External Battery Pack and Charger&lt;/a&gt;. Although it does have two USB ports, one is for charging the battery. As a backup battery it worked fine, but the solar panel is basically on there for emergencies. After a full day of riding with it in the sun I could maybe get 5% charge onto my phone. That would be great if I was stuck somewhere and had to do a quick call or text, but I wouldn't buy it for it's solar panel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="usb"></category><category term="battery"></category></entry><entry><title>Could BYOD Become a Job Requirement?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/10/29/could-byod-become-a-job-requirement/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-29T20:22:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-29T20:22:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-10-29:/2013/10/29/could-byod-become-a-job-requirement/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.mobileenterprise360.com/blogs/paulkapustka/could-byod-become-job-requirement'&gt;Could BYOD Become a Job Requirement&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Reliable transportation needed." Anyone else remember want ads with that line? The jobs in question might not have required much of a resume, but they sure did require proof of a solid vehicle to get you to work on time. Was that fair? Maybe …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.mobileenterprise360.com/blogs/paulkapustka/could-byod-become-job-requirement'&gt;Could BYOD Become a Job Requirement&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Reliable transportation needed." Anyone else remember want ads with that line? The jobs in question might not have required much of a resume, but they sure did require proof of a solid vehicle to get you to work on time. Was that fair? Maybe not, but it was the price you paid to make a buck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advances in technology, virtualization, and remote access technologies, it is becoming easier and easier to support a BYOD program. This is a logical step in the business world, one that some school districts have already taken. Do you know of anyplace that this is happening?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="byod"></category></entry><entry><title>Why are you integrating technology?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/09/23/why-are-you-integrating-technology/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-23T10:37:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-23T10:37:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-09-23:/2013/09/23/why-are-you-integrating-technology/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://georgecouros.ca/blog/archives/4125"&gt;School plus&lt;/a&gt; I have a new favorite quote for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When Gutenberg invented the printing press, we didn’t have Europe plus books. Instead we had a whole new Europe."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding technology, you want a whole new school, not just school plus technology. Go over and read &lt;a href="http://georgecouros.ca/blog/archives/4125"&gt;George …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="http://georgecouros.ca/blog/archives/4125"&gt;School plus&lt;/a&gt; I have a new favorite quote for today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When Gutenberg invented the printing press, we didn’t have Europe plus books. Instead we had a whole new Europe."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When adding technology, you want a whole new school, not just school plus technology. Go over and read &lt;a href="http://georgecouros.ca/blog/archives/4125"&gt;George Coursos' full post&lt;/a&gt;, he's hit it out of the park yet again!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="quote"></category><category term="integration"></category></entry><entry><title>The PirateBox is going Bezerk</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/06/06/the-piratebox-is-going-bezerk/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-06T16:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-06-06T16:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-06-06:/2013/06/06/the-piratebox-is-going-bezerk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My PirateBox was basically the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/MK802-Android-Google-Player-Allwinner/dp/B008BFXOZE/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370548870&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=mk802"&gt;MK802 Android mini PC&lt;/a&gt; with the top part of the case removed. This was to allow better wifi reception. Since I'll be taking the PirateBox to Cedar Point, I thought I better make it a little be more secure. I stuffed the guts into an …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My PirateBox was basically the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/MK802-Android-Google-Player-Allwinner/dp/B008BFXOZE/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370548870&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=mk802"&gt;MK802 Android mini PC&lt;/a&gt; with the top part of the case removed. This was to allow better wifi reception. Since I'll be taking the PirateBox to Cedar Point, I thought I better make it a little be more secure. I stuffed the guts into an Atari 2600 Bezerk cartridge (don't worry, this was a spare so I can still play Bezerk. I also kept the inside of the cartridge so I can even play this on if I want).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Before:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/BeserkBoxBefore-l.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And after:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/blog/BeserkBoxAfter2-l.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="piratebox"></category><category term="mk802"></category><category term="bezerk"></category></entry><entry><title>A PirateBox to call my own</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/06/05/a-piratebox-to-call-my-own/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-05T19:28:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-06-05T19:28:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-06-05:/2013/06/05/a-piratebox-to-call-my-own/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a couple of weeks I will be taking part in the Great Ohio Bike Adventure (GOBA), a week long bike ride through several towns in Ohio. As I was planning on how to power everything, somehow I was reminded of the PirateBox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://daviddarts.com/piratebox/?title=PirateBox"&gt;PirateBox&lt;/a&gt; is a self contained hotspot …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a couple of weeks I will be taking part in the Great Ohio Bike Adventure (GOBA), a week long bike ride through several towns in Ohio. As I was planning on how to power everything, somehow I was reminded of the PirateBox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://daviddarts.com/piratebox/?title=PirateBox"&gt;PirateBox&lt;/a&gt; is a self contained hotspot that runs a webserver, allowing anyone within range to connect to it and upload or download files. It also has a chat box on the front page for simple chatting needs and a simple image board. The PirateBox grew out of David Darts need to share files with his classes at NYU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first stumbled upon the idea either from &lt;a href="http://cogdogblog.com/2011/06/01/piratebox-storybox/"&gt;Alan Levine&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2011/01/piratebox-an-artistic-provocation-in-lunchbox-form/"&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt; and promptly forgot about it. With low cost computers easily accesible, I thought, why not make a PirateBox for GOBA and see what happens. As I was planning to order a Raspberry Pi (most PirateBoxes are made with a wireless router, but I like doing things the hardway) I was reminded of my &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/MK802-Android-Google-Player-Allwinner/dp/B008BFXOZE/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370475494&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=mk802"&gt;Mini MK802 Android 4.0 &lt;/a&gt; that I already had. Here was a computer a little larger than a pack of gum with 1GB of RAM and wifi. I installed &lt;a href="http://romanrm.ru/en/a10/debian"&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; on it (requires a network adapter since you have to use SSH to control it) and then used &lt;a href="http://piratebox.aod-rpg.de/dokuwiki/doku.php/piratebox_lighttpd"&gt;these directions&lt;/a&gt; to finish setting it up. On caveat, you have to apt-get install python since that isn't in the Debian image. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a restart, it didn't show up as a hotspot, so I started digging and came across &lt;a href="http://blog.sip2serve.com/post/38010690418/raspberry-pi-access-point-using-rtl8192cu"&gt;these directions on setting up an access point on a Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;. After I replaced the hostapd program with the one from the website and changed the /opt/piratebox/conf/hostapd.conf config file to match the directions, the PirateBox was in business. I also added a 16GB flash drive for shared file storage. It's formatted FAT32 so I can easily update it from my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been carrying it around with me, although I don't think anyone has connected to it that I hadn't told yet. On my trip to Cedar Point I'll be bringing it along to see what bored people standing in line will do with it. It currently has some creative commons works on it (Cory Doctorow book, some Jonathan Coulton songs) and I'll need to load more before I go. One problem that I have with it is that as soon as I leave wifi, my iPhone latches onto the PirateBox and then nothing works. I end up turning off wifi for now, at least until I come up with a better idea. One other thing I need to do is come up with a better name. I can't have PirateBox showing up in the wifi settings when I'm in the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm brainstorming what else I can do with it. I have a 1GHz machine with 1GB of RAM (it's only using 56MB of RAM) running in my pocket at all time. What neat things can I do with it?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="piratebox"></category><category term="mk802"></category><category term="debian"></category></entry><entry><title>Linux for 1:1 instead of Chromebooks or iPads</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/04/11/linux-for-11-instead-of-chromebooks-or-ipads/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-11T16:50:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-04-11T16:50:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-04-11:/2013/04/11/linux-for-11-instead-of-chromebooks-or-ipads/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(This post is basically me thinking out loud...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/saigonubuntulinux10.jpg"&gt;Like many districts, my district is looking at devices for a 1:1
program. The top three devices seem to be Chromebooks, iPads, Windows or
OS X laptops. Costs are the main driving factor for a lot of districts,
which basically means …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(This post is basically me thinking out loud...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/saigonubuntulinux10.jpg"&gt;Like many districts, my district is looking at devices for a 1:1
program. The top three devices seem to be Chromebooks, iPads, Windows or
OS X laptops. Costs are the main driving factor for a lot of districts,
which basically means they are choosing between Chromebooks or iPads.
While these devices have their uses, I'm wondering why we aren't looking
at Linux laptops (probably running Ubuntu). There are districts with
districts with Linux laptops, with &lt;a href="http://ubermix.org/"&gt;Ubermix&lt;/a&gt; being pretty prevalant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubermix has some neat features, the most important one is the ability
for a student to re-set their laptop on their own &lt;a href="http://ubermix.org/basics.html"&gt;with quick
recovery&lt;/a&gt;. In my mind, I'm thinking of extending this function along
with what I've learned from my &lt;a href="http://ryancollins.org/2013/03/13/re-purpose-old-machines-as-chrome-browser-boxes-introducing-the-gozbrowserbox/"&gt;GozBrowserBox project&lt;/a&gt;. I would
probably use the idea of Ubermix but with a straight Ubuntu install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each laptop would be set up to use &lt;a href="https://puppetlabs.com/"&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; in a serverless manner for
management and the student's home folder would be synced to a Network
Attached Storage device. The Puppet manifests would be synced and ran at
startup, and the home folder syncing would happen only at log in and log
off. Both of these to minimize any bandwidth issues. I haven't quite
figured out how to do user management. It could be done with Puppet for
1:1 managed machines, and use our current directory for shared devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup would be very, very powerful. Not only could they do
everything a Chromebook could do, but they would give the students
access to software that's not available on the web. This is a very
important consideration for students in 7th grade and lower, since most
websites limit usage by those under the age of 13. Management becomes a
non-issue with a quick recovery setup and Puppet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost per device would be between $300-$350 (without case). Comparable
Chromebooks cost $280-$310 with Google Management, and the iPad mini
starts at $329 (but can't be used with the PARCC tests, so you really
need to start at $399).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What have I missed?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="1:1"></category><category term="chromebook"></category><category term="iPad"></category><category term="linux"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category></entry><entry><title>Re-purpose old machines as Chrome Browser boxes - Introducing the GozBrowserBox</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/03/13/re-purpose-old-machines-as-chrome-browser-boxes-introducing-the-gozbrowserbox/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-13T17:23:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-03-13T17:23:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-03-13:/2013/03/13/re-purpose-old-machines-as-chrome-browser-boxes-introducing-the-gozbrowserbox/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been going back and forth on when to formally announce the
GozBrowserBox project. On one hand, I'm sure it's ready to be used, but
on the other hand, I'm afraid I forgot something! Anyway, without
further ado...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introducing the GozBrowser Box&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://mrrcollins.github.com/GozBrowserBox/loginscreen.jpg?raw=true"&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/mrrcollins/GozBrowserBox"&gt;GozBrowserBox&lt;/a&gt;
is a set of scripts that will …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been going back and forth on when to formally announce the
GozBrowserBox project. On one hand, I'm sure it's ready to be used, but
on the other hand, I'm afraid I forgot something! Anyway, without
further ado...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introducing the GozBrowser Box&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://mrrcollins.github.com/GozBrowserBox/loginscreen.jpg?raw=true"&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/mrrcollins/GozBrowserBox"&gt;GozBrowserBox&lt;/a&gt;
is a set of scripts that will take an Ubuntu installation and set up a full
screen browser box. It works very well
with lower end machines and makes them more useful. There are three
configurations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standalone: For Intel machines with at least 512MB of RAM, this
    configuration will set up the machine to launch Chrome full screen
    running on the local machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser server: For Intel machines with a couple GBs of RAM, this
    configuration sets up the machine like the standalone machine above,
    but also allows remote access for clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser client: For PowerPC machines (like eMacs, iBooks, etc) or
    Intel machines with at least 256MB of RAM (it may work with less, I
    haven't had a chance to test it). This configuration requires some
    network configuration to resolve the machine name &lt;em&gt;browser&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three configurations use Chrome to it's fullest, including Flash and
sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;INSTALLING GOZBROWSERBOX WILL TOTALLY WIPE OUT THE MACHINE IT IS BEING INSTALLED ON WITHOUT WARNING. USE AT YOUR OWN RISK!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out over on &lt;a href="https://github.com/mrrcollins/GozBrowserBox"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="chrome"></category></entry><entry><title>❂ Andre Cassagnes, Creator Of The Etch A Sketch, Dead At 86</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/02/04/andre-cassagnes-creator-of-the-etch-a-sketch-dead-at-86/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-04T13:43:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-02-04T13:43:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-02-04:/2013/02/04/andre-cassagnes-creator-of-the-etch-a-sketch-dead-at-86/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/04/andre-cassagnes-creator-of-the-etch-a-sketch-dead-at-86/"&gt;? Source ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/02/04/andre-cassagnes-creator-of-the-etch-a-sketch-dead-at-86/"&gt;? Source ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Thirty years of tech, where are we now?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2013/01/29/thirty-years-of-tech-where-are-we-now/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-29T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-01-29T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2013-01-29:/2013/01/29/thirty-years-of-tech-where-are-we-now/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/Apple_Lisa.jpg"&gt;This January marks the 30 year anniversary of the Apple //e and the
Apple Lisa. While the Apple //e had profound effects on the computer
world throughout the 80s, I am in awe of how much the Apple Lisa
foretold of the computing world. No matter what your thoughts are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://dl.ryancollins.org/Apple_Lisa.jpg"&gt;This January marks the 30 year anniversary of the Apple //e and the
Apple Lisa. While the Apple //e had profound effects on the computer
world throughout the 80s, I am in awe of how much the Apple Lisa
foretold of the computing world. No matter what your thoughts are of
Steve Jobs, the man had a knack for going "&lt;a href="http://www.complex.com/tech/2012/10/steve-jobs-quotes/move-toward-the-goal"&gt;where the puck is going to
be, not where it has been&lt;/a&gt;". Reading through &lt;a href="http://dl.ryancollins.org/BYTE%20Lisa%20Review%20-%20Feb%201983.pdf"&gt;BYTE magazine review of
the Apple Lisa&lt;/a&gt; shows what Steve was envisioning. It seems so quaint
how the writer had to describe using the "mouse", what the "desktop"
was, and how to double-click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Lisa was a failure in the marketplace and its document
centric model being bypassed by an app centric model, it did set the
stage for the direction of computers over the next 30 years. BYTE
magazine, the world's second personal computer magazine, started
publication in 1975 as a platform agnostic magazine. The Lisa was so
different that the reviewer didn't quite know how to review the
computer, and, in fact, foresaw the end of the megahertz race and the
death of computer specs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting on the technical specifications of a computer toward the end
of an article is unusual for BYTE, but it emphasizes tha the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of
Lisa is more important than the what. For part of the market, at
least, the Lisa computer will change the emphasis of microcomputer
from "How much RAM does it have?" to "What can it do for me?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lisa also had a sleep feature, much like hibernate under Windows and
how iOS on the iPhone and iPad react to sleeping and waking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... thing happens when you turn the Lisa "off" (actually, it's never
completely off; it just goes into a low-power mode). In any case, when
you hit the Off button, system software automatically closes all open
files, thus transferring the information in them to their respective
floppy disks, and releses the disks from the Lisa disk drives. In
addition, the software records the status of the "desktop" so that,
when the computer is reactivated, Lisa automatically returns it to the
appearance and state it was in when the Lisa was turned "off".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that when people try to predict the future there are only two
different scenerios. The more likely gradual changes, and the so far out
there changes that the chance of them being right is slim and
unbelievable. The Lisa shows that Apple was the latter, and it amazes me
what they were thinking up in the years leading up to its release. Apple
did get inspiration on the GUI from Xerox Parc, but their additions,
such as pull-down menus, overlapping windows, are the excence of Apple,
refinement of an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xerox PARC’s innovation had been to replace the traditional computer
command line with onscreen icons. But when you clicked on an icon you
got a pop-up menu: this was the intermediary between the user’s
intention and the computer’s response. Jobs’s software team took the
graphical interface a giant step further. It emphasized “direct
manipulation.” If you wanted to make a window bigger, you just pulled
on its corner and made it bigger; if you wanted to move a window
across the screen, you just grabbed it and moved it. The Apple
designers also invented the menu bar, the pull-down menu, and the
trash can—all features that radically simplified the original Xerox
parc idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between direct and indirect manipulation—between three
buttons and one button, three hundred dollars and fifteen dollars, and
a roller ball supported by ball bearings and a free-rolling ball—is
not trivial. It is the difference between something intended for
experts, which is what Xerox PARC had in mind, and something that’s
appropriate for a mass audience, which is what Apple had in mind. PARC
was building a personal computer. Apple wanted to build a popular
computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2011/05/16/110516fa_fact_gladwell?currentPage=all"&gt;Read more:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here we are, 30 years later. A half billion iOS devices have been
sold, and more people than ever have more computing power in their
pocket then what was used to put a man on the moon. Apple now generates
almost as much revenue in a quarter than Microsoft does in a year. With
$137 billion in the bank, what do they have planned for the future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your students, &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Powerful technology is available for $25
dollars&lt;/a&gt;, what are they going to create over the next 30 years?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="apple"></category><category term="lisa"></category></entry><entry><title>Has Apple lost it?</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2012/09/12/has-apple-lost-it/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-12T18:38:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-09-12T18:38:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2012-09-12:/2012/09/12/has-apple-lost-it/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the iPhone 5 today and updates to the iPod line. Most of
the announcements were lackluster at best, but the event laid the
groundwork for the rumored iPad mini event in October, which could be
even more disastrous than the iPhone 5 event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 5 is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple announced the iPhone 5 today and updates to the iPod line. Most of
the announcements were lackluster at best, but the event laid the
groundwork for the rumored iPad mini event in October, which could be
even more disastrous than the iPhone 5 event today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 5 is a nice upgrade, thinner and lighter, but at the same
time, it doesn’t have any feature that makes it a must upgrade for me
and my iPhone 4. This is probably more of a testimonial on how good a
phone the 4 is than what the 5 brings to the table. There are features
in the next version of iOS that I won’t be able to use, such as
turn-by-turn navigation, and, I’m assuming, Facetime over cellular, but
since there are apps I can use to replace these missing features I’m not
that worried about upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s more disturbing about todays event was the iPod line refresh.
Apple now sells the iPod shuffle, iPod nano, and iPod touch (the Classic
is still available, but it hasn’t seen an update in 3 years). The iPod
shuffle makes sense as an entry level music player, and at \$49, makes
it pretty affordable. After the shuffle comes the nano, which doesn’t
make sense at all. At least the 6th generation nano had a cool look and
could be used as a watch, this 7th generation looks like an iPod touch,
works like an iPod touch, but isn’t an iPod touch. Why would Apple waste
engineering sources on the nano? They priced it at \$149, only \$50 less
than the entry level iPod touch that includes the same amount of
storage. I just can’t think of a use case where the nano makes a better
purchase than the iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the iPod touch. At the \$199 price point, they’re now
selling the 4th generation iPod touch with 16Gb instead of just 8GB. No
other changes in the now two year old device. If you want the new iPod
touch which has several of the goodies of the iPhone 5, be prepared to
shell out \$299. You do get 32Gb at this price but is it worth a third
more than the iPod touch 4th generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the pricing of the iPod touch which is the most worrisome. Making a
guess about the iPad mini launch next month, I bet that Apple will drop
the iPad 2 and put the iPad mini in at the \$399 price. This would hand
the Christmas shopping season to Amazon, Google, and possibly Barnes and
Noble. The software for iOS is heads and shoulders above what is
available for Android, but when a parent can pick up two Kindle Fire HDs
for the price of one iPad mini, what choice do you think they’re going
to make? I really doubt they’d price the iPad mini at the same price as
the new iPod touch, but let’s say they do. It would still be a third
higher than the Kindle Fire HD, although closer in price to the Nexus 7
32GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has solid devices, well built, but their pricing expectations are
all over the place. To me, it makes sense to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep the shuffle at \$49&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;place the old nano form factor (but with bluetooth) with 8GB at \$99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 4th gen (8GB) (add bluetooth 4.0 and IPS screen) at \$149&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPod touch 5th gen (16GB) at \$199&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad mini (16GB) at \$299&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 2 (16GB) at \$399&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad 3 (16GB) at \$499&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see more and more kids getting Kindle Fires, which is now at \$159.
Apple has dominated the tablet space (and the mobile phone space in
profits), but if they don’t price their products more aggressively, they
will lose that dominance. Right now, a \$299 iPad mini would be a tough
sell in my school district when I get get a Nexus 7 (which has better
integration with Google Drive) for \$199. Forget about a \$399 iPad
mini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. Signs that Steve Jobs is gone: he would never have added that hand
strap to the iPod touch.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="apple"></category><category term="iPad"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="ipodtouch"></category></entry><entry><title>Impressions of the Nexus 7 Tablet</title><link href="https://ryancollins.org/2012/07/23/impressions-of-the-nexus-7-tablet/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-07-23T12:47:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-07-23T12:47:00-04:00</updated><author><name>mr.rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2012-07-23:/2012/07/23/impressions-of-the-nexus-7-tablet/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those that know me, ordering a Google Nexus 7 Tablet when it was
released isn't much of a surprise. I did wait a day though. :-) The
Nexus 7 Tablet joins the stable of portable devices at home, which
include a couple of iPad 1s, and iPad 3, a couple …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those that know me, ordering a Google Nexus 7 Tablet when it was
released isn't much of a surprise. I did wait a day though. :-) The
Nexus 7 Tablet joins the stable of portable devices at home, which
include a couple of iPad 1s, and iPad 3, a couple of cheap Android
tablets imported from China, an iPhone, and an HP Tablet running both
WebOS and Android Ice Cream Sandwich. My first impressions will be
mainly what I see are the pros and cons of the Nexus 7. I'm not much of
a reviewer, you can find tons of other reviews around the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hardware itself is very nice, although it doesn't have the wide
viewing angles of the iPad, it's not bad. My test for viewing angles is
to lay the device flat on a table and see how well I can see the screen.
On the iPad I can use it laying flat, the Nexus 7 is also usable, just
dim enough to make me want to pick it up. Text is very nice looking,
better than the iPad 1 or Touchpad. The high resolution screen in a 7
inch size isn't "retina" ready, but it doesn't need to be. The device
fits in the front pockets of my cargo shorts, although it is too tall to
button the top flap of the cargo pockets. It's summer, so I don't know
how it will fit in dress pants, I'll find that out at the end of August.
On one side of the device there are four gold pegs that are flush with
the edge. I'm assuming this means that a dock will be available to use
the tablet in landscape mode. Over bluetooth I was able to pair a
keyboard and mouse, which makes it quite nice to use on a desk or table.
This review is being typed in Evernote using the Logitech Ultrathin
Keyboard case from my iPad 3. It's pretty neat that the home key on the
keyboard still works. In fact, most of the keys work with it (volume,
lock, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First negative to the tablet is the wide screen aspect ratio. I've read
review bashing the iPad for it's 4:3 aspect ratio, but after using the
Nexus 7 it feels like this is a good design choice with tablets. The
16:9 ratio means that the screen isn't quite wide enough when in
portrait mode, but it's not tall enough to be used in landscape mode.
When using the Nexus 7 in landscape it feels like I'm back on my
original &lt;a href="http://www.atarimuseum.com/videogames/consoles/lynx/lynx.html" title="Atari Lynx"&gt;Atari Lynx&lt;/a&gt;. Or holding on to a 2x4 by the ends. Other than
that, there aren't any real negatives about the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is another story. While Android has progressively gotten
better, it's still not up to the polished feel of iOS. There are little
things that bother me. For example, when I'm looking at my list of apps
in Google Play, I can tap on an app to get more info or to install the
app. But, when I hit the back key, I am placed back at the top of the
list, not where I was. Annoying. Also, I had to install a different
launcher since the default launcher (think home screen) doesn't work in
landscape mode. Android still doesn't have the quality of apps that iOS
does, such as TweetBot, Paper by Fifty Three, Garageband, and iMovie. I
do need to investigate multimedia creation apps. It does have a Google
Drive app that is very nice and supports editing of word processing
documents. And the Share icon available in most apps is very nice and a
lot more usable than it is in iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onscreen keyboard still needs work. I've replaced it with SwiftKey,
which is a lot better than the default keyboard, but it's still not as
fast as typing on my iPhone or iPad. Selecting text is servicable,
although not enjoyable. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you buy it? Is this a device for schools? As of right now, I'm in
a wait and see mode. I know in the past I've said to base decisions on
what is available now, not what may be available, but with the rumor
that an 8" iPad may be announced in October, I feel patience is best.
All of the software negatives I've mentioned above can be rectified with
updates, but can they be by October? If you are a school district that
is not looking at iOS devices, the Nexus 7 tablet is a worthy contender,
especially if you are a Google Apps for Education school. This could be
the start of an one to one program that is sustainable in a lot of
districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addendum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I forgot to mention two items, battery life and charging issues. First
off, battery life. It's ok, but it's no iPad. I've found that the Nexus
7 can barely make it through a day without needing charged. The reports
of 7 hour of battery life doesn't seem quite right. Using it for web,
email, IM, and a few other things (no media playback or games) has it
last maybe 6 hours. And that goes into my next rant about charging it.
This isn't a bullet point but a RANT! The Nexus 7 will only charge with
its USB cord and its charger. I've tried different chargers, including
an iPad charger, and it won't charge. It seems to show a charge when
plugged into my MacBook Air, but it doesn't charge. What is the point of
using a mini USB for the connector if I can't charge it?!?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="android"></category><category term="nexus7"></category></entry></feed>