<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>RyanCollins.org - mri_rcollins</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//ryancollins.org/feeds/mri_rcollins.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//ryancollins.org/</id><updated>2016-01-28T20:29:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>A bash script to check domain expirations</title><link href="//ryancollins.org/2016/01/28/a-bash-script-to-check-domain-expirations/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-28T20:29:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-01-28T20:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>mri_rcollins</name></author><id>tag:ryancollins.org,2016-01-28:/2016/01/28/a-bash-script-to-check-domain-expirations/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a bad habit, and that's of buying domain names. I have about 20, with several different registrars. If I was smart, I would consolidate them under one registrar, but, even then, checking expirations on the domains is a pain. I usually have autorenew turned on, but I still …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a bad habit, and that's of buying domain names. I have about 20, with several different registrars. If I was smart, I would consolidate them under one registrar, but, even then, checking expirations on the domains is a pain. I usually have autorenew turned on, but I still like to know when they are getting close to expiration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before re-inventing the wheel, I did a Google search, and found &lt;a href="http://www.cyberciti.biz/tips/domain-check-script.html"&gt;Domain Expiration Check Shell Script&lt;/a&gt;. It worked pretty well, except for a few top level domains like .me which didn't work. I modified the script, and just had to put some finishing touches on it today (.com, .net,  and .org was broken). Check &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/mrrcollins/9a668109fa8a97f9fb90"&gt;out the gist of the script on Github&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put all of my domains in a text file, and can then run it with &lt;code&gt;./domain-check -f mydomains.txt&lt;/code&gt;. It's pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="domains"></category><category term="bash"></category></entry></feed>